<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>CMPUT 402</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cmput402.github.io/</id><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><subtitle>Software Quality</subtitle><entry><title>Group Assignment 1: Basics</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/basics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-30:/group/basics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-1-verification-of-existing-functionality"&gt;Part 1: Verification of Existing Functionality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-2-test-automation-infrastructure"&gt;Part 2: Test Automation Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#infrastructure-setup"&gt;Infrastructure Setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria-for-g1"&gt;Acceptance criteria for G1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#notes-on-screenshots"&gt;Notes on Screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this first group project is to familiarize yourself with the Tartan Home system, which you will eventually extend with new functionality
and test …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-1-verification-of-existing-functionality"&gt;Part 1: Verification of Existing Functionality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-2-test-automation-infrastructure"&gt;Part 2: Test Automation Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#infrastructure-setup"&gt;Infrastructure Setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria-for-g1"&gt;Acceptance criteria for G1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#notes-on-screenshots"&gt;Notes on Screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this first group project is to familiarize yourself with the Tartan Home system, which you will eventually extend with new functionality
and test for functional correctness, code quality, and other quality attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning goals of G1 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarize yourself with technologies/concepts such as gradle, DropWizard, Hibernate, and RESTful Web services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to to setup and manage a continuous integration strategy and supporting
  technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get experience adding tests to an existing system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following requirements must be satisfied to start this project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A development environment with Java, gradle and docker support,
  preferably together with a correctly configured IDE like Eclipse or
  IntelliJ that allows to execute unit tests and perform coverage analysis
  on Java projects. (IntelliJ is recommended but not required)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All members of the team must accept the assignment on GitHub classroom on the following link &lt;a href="https://classroom.github.com/a/v-Nv1id7"&gt;https://classroom.github.com/a/v-Nv1id7&lt;/a&gt;. This will create the private repository your team will work on. Please note that your teams are already created on eClass. Make sure to join your assigned team. &lt;strong&gt;The first person from your team to accept the assignment on GitHub classroom will create the team there. Use the same team name as on eClass (e.g., Group1, Group15 etc)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also likely need several additional tools to complete this assignment.
Please identify and describe these tools in your report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all submissions, make sure to explicitly mention your group number and all group memeber names and CCIDs, as well as your team's GitHub repo. You should also edit your repo's ReadMe file to include your group name and members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="part-1-verification-of-existing-functionality"&gt;Part 1: Verification of Existing Functionality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;four&lt;/em&gt; test cases for Tartan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following describe Tartan's rule for making decisions about the house state. Your first tasks is to select &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;four&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of these rules and assess that they are correctly implemented. You will write one unit test for each of selected rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R1:&lt;/strong&gt; If the house is vacant, then the light cannot be turned on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R2:&lt;/strong&gt; If the alarm is enabled, and the door gets opened, then sound the alarm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R3:&lt;/strong&gt; If the house is vacant, then close the door.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R4:&lt;/strong&gt; If the alarm is enabled and the house gets suddenly occupied (i.e., someone is detected by the proximity sensor), then sound the alarm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R5:&lt;/strong&gt; If the house is empty, then start the away timer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R6:&lt;/strong&gt; When the away timer expires, then turn off the light, arm the alarm, and close the door.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R7:&lt;/strong&gt; If the house becomes occupied while the alarm is disabled, then turn on the lights for the legitimate user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R8:&lt;/strong&gt; The alarm can be disabled &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; when the house is occupied (i.e. it cannot be disabled remotely).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R9:&lt;/strong&gt; The correct passcode is required to disable the alarm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R10:&lt;/strong&gt; If the target temperature is greater than the current temperature, then turn on the heater. Otherwise, turn off the heater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R11:&lt;/strong&gt; If the target temperature is less than the current temperature, then turn on the air conditioner. Otherwise, turn off the air conditioner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R12:&lt;/strong&gt; The heater and the dehumidifier cannot be run simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you need to only implement one unit test for each selected rule. In G2, you will be asked to implement additional tests as needed. For the purpose of G1, you can assume independence between the rules (i.e., you do not need to think about situations that combine multiple rules). You will think about that for G2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For G1, in most cases you probably won't have to check the opposite scenario for the test cases. For example: for the test case "If the house is vacant, then the light cannot be turned on.", you can not assert the opposite scenario here that "if the house has occupants, turn off the lights". This does not work because an occupant of the house can turn off the lights while sleeping or keep them on while working. Make sure that you are keeping these things in mind while implementing the test cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, you only have to implement whatever is required for the test cases and use your best judgement as to how to make the test cases work. But for some test cases, for example: R12, you will have to check both scenarios, like what happens if one is on and one is off and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find that any of the functionality are not correctly implemented, you must indicate the problem you found in your report and how you fixed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="part-2-test-automation-infrastructure"&gt;Part 2: Test Automation Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have written your initial tests and understand how to build and run Tartan, you will set up the infrastructure necessary to automate building and testing. You will set up and configure
&lt;a href="https://github.com/features/actions"&gt;GitHub (GH) Actions&lt;/a&gt; in your own
repository to be used for the rest of the semester. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="infrastructure-setup"&gt;Infrastructure Setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up and configure GH Actions workflow in your repository. As a minimum, your team should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up GH Actions in the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automate the build and tests of the Tartan Home system using workflows (use the tests you wrote in Part 1 to try out and demonstrate the infrastructure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure GH Actions to automatically trigger a new build whenever changes
  are pushed to your GH repository (e.g., main branch).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you are also welcome to explore additional GH Actions that may provide useful functionality, for example, actions that show statistics, test coverage, or track performance results. You may find this
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sdras/awesome-actions"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; useful if you want to set up
additional workflows. This is not required for G1 but may prove useful for your next group projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="acceptance-criteria-for-g1"&gt;Acceptance criteria for G1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit a short (max. 3 pages) informal &lt;strong&gt;PDF&lt;/strong&gt; report on eClass that:
- mentions the four rules you chose and the name/location of the corresponding tests
- &lt;em&gt;briefly&lt;/em&gt; describes your infrastructure setup (i.e., the list of GH actions/workflows you set up and how these workflows build the code and run the tests). 
- includes one or more screenshots that show (1) a successful build, (2) a failing build, and (3) the passing tests from Part 1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="notes-on-screenshots"&gt;Notes on Screenshots&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the passing build, it is enough to share a screenshot of a successful Github Actions workflow run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the failing build, it needs to be a result of a build failure (e.g., due to compilation issues) or test failure (i.e., a test did not pass). Failures caused by wrong setup of your workflow (e.g., permission issues, "No such file or directory" errors, etc.) are NOT examples of a failing build. These are examples of a failed setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the passing tests, the screenshot must include the name of the passing test. Thus, it needs to be screenshot of either an IDE test execution window or the test report that gets generated by Gradle (located in the file &lt;code&gt;build/reports/tests/test/index.html&lt;/code&gt;) such that name of the passing test can be seen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following criteria must be satisfied for G1 to be accepted as
complete. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Criteria&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Four unit tests that verify the functionality of three rules and run successfully (i.e., passes)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;A description of any bugs found in the system through the test &amp;amp; how they were fixed as applicable. If no bugs found, an explicit statement is required.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;The test infrastructure is set up with automated building and testing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Github Actions platform reports when the build (i.e., either compilation or tests) is passing/failing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please tag your code with &lt;code&gt;G1_Done&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, G1 is worth 80 points with the following allocation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceptance criteria: 65 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report: 10 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer assessment: 5 points (assigned individually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report is graded based on its presentation, organization, and how clearly things are described. All the items described in the Acceptance Criteria section above must appear in the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each member must assess their team members' contributions on eClass. This is worth 5 points of the total assignment grade and is confidential (results go to the course staff). Note that if we find big discrepencies in contributions or if one team members is negatively rated by all other team members, then we will investigate and regrade team members as needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2021, 2022 Dr. Sarah Nadi. Copyright 2023, 2024 Dr. Hazel Campbell. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="group"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Assignment 2: Testing</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-30:/group/testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-1-improve-test-suite"&gt;Part 1: Improve Test Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria-for-part-1"&gt;Acceptance criteria for Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-2-implementation-and-verification-of-a-smart-door-lock"&gt;Part 2: Implementation and Verification of a Smart Door Lock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria-for-part-2"&gt;Acceptance criteria for Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#report-for-parts-1-2"&gt;Report for Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#questions-you-should-be-able-to-answer-after-this-assignment"&gt;Questions You Should Be Able to Answer After This Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, you will extend …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-1-improve-test-suite"&gt;Part 1: Improve Test Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria-for-part-1"&gt;Acceptance criteria for Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#part-2-implementation-and-verification-of-a-smart-door-lock"&gt;Part 2: Implementation and Verification of a Smart Door Lock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria-for-part-2"&gt;Acceptance criteria for Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#report-for-parts-1-2"&gt;Report for Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#questions-you-should-be-able-to-answer-after-this-assignment"&gt;Questions You Should Be Able to Answer After This Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, you will extend the Tartan Home system with new functionality
and test it for functional correctness, code quality, and quality attributes.
You will conduct this testing at multiple levels (e.g., unit, integration, and
system) primarily to verify functional correctness of existing and new code.
You may also need to modify your testing infrastructure from G1, as needed. The assignment
requires teams to extend the system to support a new smart door lock with
several features and test that functionality. G2 has two parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning goals of this group project are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to to setup and manage a continuous testing strategy and supporting
  technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain experience using different test case design techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select and integrate appropriate testing techniques throughout the
  engineering process, using appropriate technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select and assess various measures, including but not limited to code
  coverage, for the adequacy of a test suite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following requirements must be satisfied to start this project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The team is familiar with collaborative development and code review
  features of Github (a quick recap will also be provided in the lab).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A development environment with Java, gradle and docker support,
  preferably together with a correctly configured IDE like Eclipse or
  IntelliJ that allows to execute unit tests and perform coverage analysis
  on Java projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that you must continue working on the same repository you created through GitHub classroom for group project 1. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also likely need several additional tools to complete this assignment.
Please identify and describe these tools in your report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="part-1-improve-test-suite"&gt;Part 1: Improve Test Suite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In G1, you were still starting out with Tartan and did not know of all the techniques that can help you choose meaningful test cases and also assess the quality of your tests. Additionally, you only implemented one test per feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this assignment, your task is to improve the quality of your test suite for the four rules you chose in G1 as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use blackbox testing techniques to create better test cases and corresponding oracles (i.e., the concrete input values and expected output in your tests). You are advised to carefully read Tartan's specification and decide on whether there are additional scenarios you need to test for (e.g., now is time to think about whether the rules interact and if there are edge cases you need to think of). When selecting concrete oracles, some of your options include boundary value testing, random testing, or strong/weak equivalence class testing. You may think of other strategies too. Although you will work on your selected four rules for the blackbox testing, you need to think about all variables (old and new) of the evaluateState() function and how changing one particular state might affect your selected rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use whitebox testing techniques to evaluate and improve the adequacy of your test suite. In this case, you are asked to write more tests that improve the coverage of your test suite to 80%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not need to be 80% of the entire system: you only need 80% coverage of the methods that implement your four rules. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the code coverage tutorial posted on eClass and discussed in the lab to see how you can configure your coverage measurement tool to measure coverage only for your selected features. However, you must include &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; all methods your blackbox tests interact with either directly or indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="acceptance-criteria-for-part-1"&gt;Acceptance criteria for Part 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following criteria must be satisfied for Part 1 to be accepted as
complete. A description of the report you must submit is provided at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Criteria&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Whitebox and blackbox test design and selection plans are completed and explained.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Automated measurement of coverage with each build is implemented&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;All tests pass.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Tests must achieve at least 80% statement and 80% branch coverage for the &lt;em&gt;features selected to test.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id="part-2-implementation-and-verification-of-a-smart-door-lock"&gt;Part 2: Implementation and Verification of a Smart Door Lock&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tartan Inc. would like your team to implement the software logic for a new smart
door lock. The smart door lock hardware allows the door to be locked and
unlocked automatically using a passcode, and it will provide many "smart"
features that users can configure for additional security or convenience. Note that opening/closing the door is different from locking/unlocking a lock. The former refers to the physical state of the door while the latter refers to the state of the deadbolt on the door.
Specifically, the smart lock must support the following features that users
can enable or disable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electronic Operation:&lt;/em&gt; If a person requests a lock or unlock operation
  from an access panel, first check if that operation requires a
  passcode. If it does, read and check the passcode. If the passcode is refused, send a message to the access panel. Otherwise, perform the requested operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keyless Entry:&lt;/em&gt; When sensors detect a resident arriving on the
  property (e.g., proximity of a registered cell phone), automatically unlock the door.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intruder Defense:&lt;/em&gt; When sensors in the house detect the possible presence
  of an intruder, lock the door and send "possible intruder detected"
  messages to the access panels. Keep the door locked until the sensors
  provide an "all clear" signal, at which time "all clear" messages are
  sent to the access panels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Night Lock:&lt;/em&gt; Residents configure the time when night begins and ends. At
  night, automatically lock the door and always relock it if it becomes
  unlocked at any point during the night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that, the access panel is a physical object, you'll have to write necessary code for this to make it work. It is not the log that you have been using in G1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the above feature requirements may be ambiguous. In addition, features
may interact and the door lock should behave in a reasonable way, which can be
resolved with timers, priorities, or other mechanisms. For example, what
happens or should happen if an intruder is detected and a resident arrives at
the door? You should ask for clarification about requirements if needed and
explicitly document all assumptions you make about interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrate the smart door lock and its features with the current system and test
it thoroughly. You can add additional sensors and actuators to the house, if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While developing the new door lock features, you must follow a test-driven approach.&lt;/strong&gt;
Use Pull Requests to integrate each new functionality and have another team member review your code. &lt;strong&gt;Each team member must perform a code review of
at least 1 PR.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make it easier for us to spot your test-driven development, you must make your commits
using a specific pattern that shows that you have worked using TDD. Make a
git commit after each of the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red: Write a test that fails. Make a commit with the word "RED" at the beginning of the commit message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green: Change the implementation so that the test succeeds. Make a commit with the word "GREEN".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactor: Rewrite the code. Make a commit with the word "REFACTOR". Your tests must still pass after this change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must conduct unit testing on the new code and carefully measure coverage.
However, given that this is a new feature, you should also perform integration (i.e., tests that combine multiple classes/functionality) and system testing (i.e., end to end testing that treats the system as a black box). You must document the integration and system testing
procedures in your report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="acceptance-criteria-for-part-2"&gt;Acceptance criteria for Part 2&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following criteria must be satisfied for the assignment to be accepted as
complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Criteria&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Requirements for the smart door lock are documented. The documentation format is up to the team, but should be clear and complete and includes any assumptions the team made.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;The software for the smart door lock successfully builds, runs, and implements stated requirements.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Integration and system testing strategy is implemented and described&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Tests must achieve at least 80% statement and 80% branch coverage for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; code.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;The mutation score for the tests related to the new door lock functionality should be 90%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Test-driven development has been followed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;New features underwent code review&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id="report-for-parts-1-2"&gt;Report for Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a report as a single &lt;strong&gt;PDF&lt;/strong&gt; file that describes your verification
activities, decisions, and results for both the existing functionality and the
new door lock (max. 4 pages of text, not including screenshots/tables etc). You must upload your report to eClass by the specified deadline. While marking, we will verify all acceptance criteria by checking both your report and code repository.
&lt;strong&gt;The final version of your code for all parts of this project must be in the master branch and tagged as &lt;code&gt;G2_Done&lt;/code&gt; by the deadline.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following describe the required details of the report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chosen Rules&lt;/strong&gt;: For completeness, restate the four rules you chose for part 1 (they should be the same as those from G1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing plan and test cases&lt;/strong&gt;: Describe the
  process you used to design test cases and provide an overview of the tests
  you wrote. How were test cases designed? How were test values selected? Which
  testing techniques did you use (i.e. random testing, combinatorial testing,
  BVA, other)? Mention how much additional testing you needed to add in G2 when compared to G1. Finally, provide a pointer to the actual test classes/methods scripts in your repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: Provide a screenshot of your coverage report (you can focus only on the relevant parts of the system). While marking, we will look into the actual report ourselves and make sure you satisfy the coverage criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 2&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clarified requirements for smart door lock&lt;/strong&gt;:
  Describe all assumptions you made about the requirements of the smart door
  lock system and its features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software development processes&lt;/strong&gt;: Briefly indicate
  the role of each group member in this process, describe how you planned and
  organized the design, development, and evaluation of the smart door lock.
  Include a description of how you coordinated implementation and
  testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall testing strategy and implementation:&lt;/strong&gt; . Indicate where your unit, integration, and system tests are implemented. Mention what you chose to test for integration testing as well as system testing. Which tools/frameworks/techniques did you use to implement your integration and system testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage and mutation score:&lt;/strong&gt; Provide a screenshot of your coverage report (you can focus only on the relevant parts of the system). While marking, we will look into the actual report ourselves and make sure you satisfy the coverage criteria. Also, provide a screenshot of your mutation score report. Please mention 2-3 examples of initially live mutations (i.e., mutants that your test suite did not initially kill) and how you improved your test suite to kill these mutants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, this project is worth 120 points with the following allocation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 1 (improving test suite): 40 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 2 (implementation and verification): 65 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report: 10 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer assessment: 5 points (Assigned individually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report is graded based on its presentation, organization, and how clearly things are described. All the items described in the Report section above must appear in the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each member must assess their team members' contributions on eClass. This is worth 5 points of the total assignment grade and is confidential (results go to the course staff). Note that if we find big discrepencies in contributions or if one team members is negatively rated by all other team members, then we will investigate and regrade team members as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="questions-you-should-be-able-to-answer-after-this-assignment"&gt;Questions You Should Be Able to Answer After This Assignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a unit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does TDD differ from standard types of testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is an Oracle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What might you need to change in the System Under Test in order to make good use of unit testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What makes black box testing different from white box testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why might we want to use black box testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the purpose of unit-testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are equivalence partitioning and boundary value analysis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do we use TDD? What is its purpose?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we always have 100% code-coverage?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the different types of coverage criteria?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does 100% coverage mean we are bug-free?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does 100% MCDC coverage mean we are bug-free?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we prove that we’re 100% bug-free?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In TDD, Why do we go for RED first?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you handle interactions in the requirements in part 2?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you test for intereactions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the computed adequacy criteria give you confidence that your software is thoroughly tested and of adequate quality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you could pick your own goals for test adequacy measures, what would you aim for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which testing techniques were most effective for you and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which techniques were less effective and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did mutation testing help you find weaknesses in your test suite? Can you give an example?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you had to conduct a similar project again, would you change any of your testing or planning strategies?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What were the challenges you faced and how did you solve them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2021, 2022 Dr. Sarah Nadi. Copyright 2023, 2024 Dr. Hazel Campbell. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="group"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Assignment 3: Testing in Production</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/testing-in-production.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-30:/group/testing-in-production.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tasks"&gt;Tasks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#continuous-deployment"&gt;Continuous deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#ab-testing"&gt;AB testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria"&gt;Acceptance Criteria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#code-and-scripts-and-documentation"&gt;Code and Scripts and Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#report"&gt;Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, you will build infrastructure for Tartan in order to conduct tests in
production. First, you will deploy your application with &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/resources/what-container"&gt;Docker
containers&lt;/a&gt; and automate
deployment into production as well …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tasks"&gt;Tasks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#continuous-deployment"&gt;Continuous deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#ab-testing"&gt;AB testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#acceptance-criteria"&gt;Acceptance Criteria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#code-and-scripts-and-documentation"&gt;Code and Scripts and Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#report"&gt;Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, you will build infrastructure for Tartan in order to conduct tests in
production. First, you will deploy your application with &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/resources/what-container"&gt;Docker
containers&lt;/a&gt; and automate
deployment into production as well as making it easy to roll back changes.
Second, you will extend the project and build an AB testing infrastructure that
can be used to assess specific changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design an AB-testing infrastructure to run tests in production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy the system through a virtualized infrastructure and support rapid updates and rollback operations with test automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can continue to work on the same Tartan Home repository you created through GitHub classroom for the previous projects. Please check eClass for deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tasks"&gt;Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id="continuous-deployment"&gt;Continuous deployment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having learned about continuous deployment, members of your company are curious
to try it. You will investigate Docker containers and run your infrastructure
in containers. You can also run the house simulators in Docker containers if
you like. Because your company does not have in-house server machines, your
company is going to acquire VM resources from
&lt;a href="https://cloud.cybera.ca/"&gt;Cybera&lt;/a&gt;.  Since Cybera uses
&lt;a href="https://www.openstack.org/software/"&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; to manage its computing
resources, you will also use it to create your own VM instance. After creating
and configuring that instance (e.g., associate floating (public) IP address,
install Docker), you will deploy and run your containers there. Note that we
already provided a setup for Docker (&lt;code&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/code&gt; file) with the
original release that you are welcome to use or modify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to extend your build and test automation, such that Docker containers for all
backend services (controller, database, and possibly additional services you
may create) are &lt;em&gt;created automatically&lt;/em&gt; every time you push a commit to GitHub
and it passes all tests. You can either &lt;em&gt;launch&lt;/em&gt; the new containers
automatically, replacing the currently running ones, or provide a lightweight
mechanisms where a human operator can launch a new version with a single button
or command-line instruction. (The house simulators are not part of the backend
and should usually continue running while the controller is updated.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, implement a technique for how to undo a release and revert back
to the previous version. Similar to releasing new versions, undoing a release
should be possible with a single button click or command-line instruction. Make sure to test your roll-back technique and to fully document the exact steps that should be done to perform a roll back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of this assignment, it is not necessary to roll out changes
incrementally or build a canary test infrastructure. However, you may possibly
need to slightly modify controller or houses to deal with short-term connection failures during updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="ab-testing"&gt;AB testing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to automating deployment, you will extend the Tartan Smart Home
system with a &lt;strong&gt;reporting feature&lt;/strong&gt; that sends customers weekly or monthly reports
about how they use their system. You will then design an experimentation
infrastructure in which you test different versions of the reporting "in
production" to see whether customers change their behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have significant flexibility in the assignment in deciding what kind of
reporting you add and what kind of experiments you want to run. For example,
you may find inspiration from decades of
&lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0378778894009124"&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt;
that analyze what kind of information in electricity bills actually encourage
customers to reduce their electricity consumption, but you can also report on
other behavior of the smart home, such as temperature, door locking status,
etc. Note that building the experiment infrastructure is more important than
the actual experiments and certainly more important than whether your new
reporting feature looks pretty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this assignment, you may want to change multiple parts of the system or may
be able to work only with modular additions (e.g., adding a new microservice
for reporting and another one for configuration and analysis). Given that you
cannot actually test with a production system yet (the team developing the
hardware for the houses is still not ready, *sigh*), you may want to change the
simulation infrastructure to have more houses and houses with different
behavior to test your infrastructure in simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a reporting system that creates reports for each customer with a Tartan Smart Home installation, reporting an aspect of your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build an experimentation infrastructure that (a) allows you to send different
  versions of the reports to different customers or at different times, (b) analyzes whether these changes have an effect on outcomes of how these customers use the system. You may need to modify how you track different customers and you may need to collect additional data about outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end of the experimentaiton period, generate some form of visualization (e.g., chart, graph, table whether as an html page or as a downloadable file) that shows which report variant was sent to which customer and how it affected them. For example, perhaps they now turned their lights off more often or decreased the average temperature of their home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="acceptance-criteria"&gt;Acceptance Criteria&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following criteria must be satisfied for the assignment to be accepted as
complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Criteria (Continuous Deployment)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;The system, including the simulation of houses and the new experimentation infrastructure is deployed with Docker containers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;All changes that pass the automated test suites are &lt;em&gt;automatically built&lt;/em&gt; as deployable Docker containers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;deployment&lt;/em&gt; of newly built versions of the docker containers on the virtual machine is either fully automated or can be done with a single command that is described in the repository's readme file or wiki.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Reverting the running system to the previous version can be be achieved with a single command that is described in the repository's readme file or wiki.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Criteria (AB Testing)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;A reporting system has been implemented that can periodically send reports to customers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;An experimentation infrastructure has been implemented that tracks which customers should see which variants of the software.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;An analysis infrastructure has been implemented that can evaluate the outcome of experiments (given one metric, how did customer's behavior change)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;An experiment has been conducted using the experimentation infrastructure, sending different variants of the report to different customers and observing different outcomes.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id="deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id="code-and-scripts-and-documentation"&gt;Code and Scripts and Documentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commit all infrastructure configuration and scripts to your git repository. Commit your code of your reporting feature and experiment
infrastructure to your git repository. &lt;strong&gt;The final version of your code should be
in the master branch of each repository, and it should be tagged as &lt;code&gt;G3-done&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include technical documentation of how to launch containers, update containers after a build, and revert containers as part of your repositories README.md file or GitHub wiki. If you choose to use the wiki, make sure that you state that in the README. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="report"&gt;Report&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a report as a single PDF file that describes your design and experiments
(figures, screenshots, etc do not count toward the page limit). Describe the
following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reporting feature&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;lt;1 page text): Describe your reporting feature and the
  goal for which you are optimizing (e.g., reducing energy consumption);
  include an example of a report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment design&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;lt; 1 page text): Describe your experiment(s): what are the
  experimental conditions (independent variables) and measured outcomes
  (dependent variables) and how you measure those.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experimentation infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;lt; 1 page text): Describe how you assign
  experimental conditions: how you implement experimental conditions (e.g.,
  branches, feature flags); how you assign control and treatment groups; and a
  short justification why you chose this implementation/design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;lt;1 page text): Describe how you analyze the outcome of the experiment. We encourage you to include a screenshot showing
  the outcome of your experiment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grading-summary"&gt;Grading Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is graded out of 155 points according to the following breakdown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Deployment: 60&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AB Testing: 70&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report: 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReadMe: 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer assessment: 5 (assigned individually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report is graded based on its presentation, organization, and how clearly things are described. All the items described in the Report section above must appear in the report. The ReadMe is graded based on whether all instructions we need to run things are there or not (Be very explicit. Do not assume we know how to run things)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each member must assess their team members' contributions on eClass. This is worth 5 points of the total assignment grade and is confidential (results go to the course staff). Note that if we find big discrepencies in contributions or if one team members is negatively rated by all other team members, then we will investigate and regrade team members as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2021, 2022 Dr. Sarah Nadi. Copyright 2023, 2024 Dr. Hazel Campbell. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="group"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Assignment 4: Static Analysis</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/static-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-30:/group/static-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#spotbugs"&gt;SpotBugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#pmd"&gt;PMD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#errorprone"&gt;ErrorProne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#task"&gt;Task&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#questions-you-should-be-able-to-answer-after-this-assignment"&gt;Questions you should be able to answer after this assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning goals of this project are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain experience using a static analysis tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand what types of defects can and cannot be found with static analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critically evaluate the results of static …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#spotbugs"&gt;SpotBugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#pmd"&gt;PMD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#errorprone"&gt;ErrorProne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#task"&gt;Task&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#questions-you-should-be-able-to-answer-after-this-assignment"&gt;Questions you should be able to answer after this assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning goals of this project are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain experience using a static analysis tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand what types of defects can and cannot be found with static analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critically evaluate the results of static analysis tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will run a static analysis tool on the same Tartan project your group has been using. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will use the following static analysis tools to analyze your Tartan codebase for potential problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SpotBugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PMD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ErrorProne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="spotbugs"&gt;SpotBugs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of ways to integrate &lt;a href="https://spotbugs.github.io/"&gt;SpotBugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Through &lt;a href="https://plugins.gradle.org/plugin/com.github.spotbugs"&gt;Gradle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standalone by downloading the binary distribution and running it as a Java application. See &lt;a href="https://spotbugs.readthedocs.io/en/stable/installing.html"&gt;installing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://spotbugs.readthedocs.io/en/stable/running.html"&gt;running&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a &lt;a href="https://spotbugs.readthedocs.io/en/stable/links.html#ide-integration"&gt;plugin for IntelliJ IDEA or Eclipse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="pmd"&gt;PMD&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href="https://docs.gradle.org/current/userguide/pmd_plugin.html"&gt;the guide for PMD Gradle Plugin&lt;/a&gt; to integrate &lt;a href="https://pmd.github.io/"&gt;PMD&lt;/a&gt; to your build system. You can also use the &lt;a href="https://pmd.github.io/latest/pmd_userdocs_installation.html#running-pmd-via-command-line"&gt;CLI option&lt;/a&gt; which does not require you to make changes to your &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="errorprone"&gt;ErrorProne&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href="https://github.com/tbroyer/gradle-errorprone-plugin"&gt;the guide for Gradle ErrorProne Plugin&lt;/a&gt; to integrate &lt;a href="https://errorprone.info/"&gt;ErrorProne&lt;/a&gt; to your build. Please pay extra attention to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/tbroyer/gradle-errorprone-plugin#jdk-8-support"&gt;Java 8 support&lt;/a&gt; section as ErrorProne requires at least JDK 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="task"&gt;Task&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run SpotBugs, PMD and ErrorProne on your Tartan system and analyze the results. Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(5 marks) Report how many errors/warnings were reported by each tool and in which categories (note that the category names or how errors/warnings are categorized in each tool may be different for each tool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(5 marks) Report the similarities and discrepencies between the tools. Are there errors/warnings that one tool reports but the other doesn't (give at least 3 examples, if available)? Are there error/warnings that all three tools report? (give at least 3 examples, if available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(5 marks) Report which Java class(es) from Tartan seems most problematic. Explain your result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(60 marks total) Select 10 reported problems, distributed across the three tools, to analyze in more detail. For each problem, report&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2 marks) The identifying information for the bug, including its category, priority, file name, and line number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1 mark) A one-sentence description of the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2 marks) A characterization of the bug in terms of whether it is an actual problem, false positive, or irrelevant true positive. Explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1 mark) How you fixed the problem (if you decided it was actually a problem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(5 marks) Peer-rating of group members. This is assigned individually. Note that if we find big discrepencies in contributions or if one team members is negatively rated by all other team members, then we will investigate and regrade team members as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your submission will include a PDF report with the above information. The total points for this assignment is 80 marks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="questions-you-should-be-able-to-answer-after-this-assignment"&gt;Questions you should be able to answer after this assignment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a false positive?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a false negative?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there problems in the code that the tool did not catch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does running a static analysis tool replace the need for testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2021, 2022 Dr. Sarah Nadi. Copyright 2023, 2024 Dr. Hazel Campbell. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="group"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Assignment 5: Technical Debt</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/technical-debt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-30:/group/technical-debt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tools"&gt;Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#task"&gt;Task&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-expectations"&gt;Grading &amp;amp; Expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complete your evaluation of the Tartan Home Platform and your enhancements, you will assess its technical debt and existing issues using SonarQube with an emphasis on how difficult the software will be to maintain going forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major development is over and the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tools"&gt;Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#task"&gt;Task&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-expectations"&gt;Grading &amp;amp; Expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complete your evaluation of the Tartan Home Platform and your enhancements, you will assess its technical debt and existing issues using SonarQube with an emphasis on how difficult the software will be to maintain going forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major development is over and the software is nearly ready to ship. As part of project wrap-up, management wants to assess the overall quality of the project based on SonarQube’s metrics and recommendations so they can correct lingering issues and reduce technical debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goals of this project are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain experience with a quality management tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use technical debt to assess the quality of a software system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflect how design and development decisions made impact quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tools"&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will use SonarQube (&lt;a href="http://www.sonarqube.org"&gt;http://www.sonarqube.org&lt;/a&gt;) to analyze your software for this project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="task"&gt;Task&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, you will evaluate the technical debt in the Tartan Home Platform. Given sensitive customer data in the system, the sponsor is still concerned about the possibility that hackers might spy on, or meddle with a home. On the other hand, after extending the system over the past few months, and with more enhancements expected in the future, the team is more concerned about how difficult it will be to change the code.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to evaluate and describe the current technical debt to the project's stakeholders and argue whether paying back (part of) the debt now is essential or not. To do so, you will evaluate your project with SonarQube, but you may choose to perform additional assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To load the Tartan Home Platform into SonarQube, do the following: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a number of ways to import the Tartan Home Platform into Sonar. Examples include: &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a Sonar Scanner: &lt;a href="https://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SCAN/Analyzing+with+SonarQube+Scanner"&gt;https://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SCAN/Analyzing+with+SonarQube+Scanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Recommended) Use Sonar Scanner with gradle: &lt;a href="https://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SCAN/Analyzing+with+SonarQube+Scanner+for+Gradle"&gt;https://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SCAN/&lt;/a&gt;. You may want to show the results of SonarQube in your CI build, but this is not required for this project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once loaded, open the project in SonarQube or view the results of the scan in your CI build (If you installed SonarQube locally this will be through a web browser; default url: &lt;a href="http://localhost:9000"&gt;http://localhost:9000&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the final assignment that involves analysis and development of the Tartan Home Platform. The focus is on reflecting on the quality assurance strategies used throughout the semester and the use of tools like SonarQube to assess and operationalize technical debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your team must submit a report on the technical debt in the project. You will also present your findings in class. Your report should report the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate the quality of your project. You must analyze and explain the technical debt that may exist in your project. Make sure to include the results/snapshots from SonarQube.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate the usefulness of SonarQube's reports. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the ratings (Maintainability, Reliability, and Security) provided by SonarQube correspond to your intuition/impression of working with Tartan? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which other SonarQube metrics or graphs were useful for your analysis of technical debt? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which parts of your the code base (i.e., classes, modules, packages etc) were ranked the best and worst?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do the new features or changes you made compare to the existing code that you started with? Have you added more debt or have you paid back some debt? (you will need to compare technical debt of the original Tartan code to the current version after the changes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, evaluate whether your current CI pipeline (without use of SonarQube) and its logs are useful for assessing technical debt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the current metrics, would you advise your team to pay back (part of) the technical debt right now before developing the new features in the pipeline? Why or why not? Make sure to elaborate your recommendation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would you adjust SonarQube or GitHub actions (or any equivalent CI pipeline) to assess technical debt in the future? Would you continue to use these tools? Would you introduce/eliminate rules or reports? Change quality profiles and quality gates? Why? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report should be no more than five pages in length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must also prepare an &lt;strong&gt;8 minute presentation&lt;/strong&gt; that summarizes the report, addressing your team’s evaluation of technical debt in your system and a reflection on the overall quality of the Tartan Home System. &lt;strong&gt;All group members are expected to be part of the presentation.&lt;/strong&gt; Note that your presentation will be in the lab before your report is due. Your presentation should cover the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with a &lt;strong&gt;quick&lt;/strong&gt; overview of your CI pipeline and all the quality tools/measures you incorporated in your Tartan system throughout the term. Some teams may have chosen to use additional tools beyond what was required in the project assignments. Please discuss this tools and the rationale for using them, as applicable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present the above 5 points from your report. You do not need to present them in the same order, but you do need to provide a good summary of the complete reflection process. Choose the most entertaining way to do this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please upload a pdf of your slides to eClass along with your report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grading-expectations"&gt;Grading &amp;amp; Expectations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This assignment is worth 90 points, allocated as follows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we will use both the content of your report and presentation to grade the following components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality evaluation using SonarQube (points 1 &amp;amp; 2 above): 30 points &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion on using your current CI pipeline for technical debt assessment: 10 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on paying back current debt: 15 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion of metrics and tool adjustments/customizations: 10 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer-rating of group members: 5 points (assigned individually). Ratings are confidential (results go to the course staff). Note that if we find big discrepencies in contributions or if one team members is negatively rated by all other team members, then we will investigate and regrade team members as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be an additional 20 points allocated to the presentation quality, based on the following crtieria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slides are well-designed (readable fonts, not cluttered, not completely text based, meaningful titles, slide numbers etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All team members speak clearly and loudly in an engaging way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation flows well and the audience undertsands what is presented at each point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of well-explained figures/charts etc to backup presented points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points will be deducted if your report is unstructured or not understandable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2021, 2022 Dr. Sarah Nadi. Copyright 2023, 2024 Dr. Hazel Campbell. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="group"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Individual Assignment 1: Testing Theory</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/individual/testing-theory.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-30:/individual/testing-theory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Individual Assignment 1: Testing Theory&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#submission"&gt;Submission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#question-1-6-marks"&gt;Question 1 (6 marks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#question-2-6-marks"&gt;Question 2 (6 marks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#question-3-7-marks"&gt;Question 3 (7 marks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#question-4-19-marks"&gt;Question 4 (19 marks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="submission"&gt;Submission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please upload a &lt;strong&gt;pdf&lt;/strong&gt; on eClass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please draw all diagrams using any program of your choice such that
    your TA can clearly read it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The assignment consists of 4 questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning objectives of this assignment is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop equivalence classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gain experience in combinatorial testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify states and transitions from a high-level description of a
    problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create simple control flow graphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;calculate different types of coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that it is important for you to understand how to solve the
problems in this assignment, as you will get similar types of problems
in the exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assignment is out of 38 marks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="question-1-6-marks"&gt;Question 1 (6 marks)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are evaluating a system that requires a user to login with a
"strong" password. The password must satisfy the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimum length: 10 characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least two uppercase characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one special symbol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to combinatorially test the &lt;code&gt;resetPassword&lt;/code&gt; function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;boolean resetPassword (String newPwd);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;resetPassword&lt;/code&gt; function takes a string as an input and returns true
if the password meets the above requirements. If the password does not
meet stated requirements, then the new password is rejected and
&lt;code&gt;resetPassword&lt;/code&gt; returns false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create concrete test cases for this function, you will decompose the
relevant dimensions of the password constraints. Use
&lt;a href="https://github.com/snadi/tslgenerator"&gt;TSLGenerator&lt;/a&gt; to help you
generate the test frames. Your steps are roughly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify equivalence classes for the password inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translate the specification from Step 1 to TSL's format and generate
    an all-pairs test specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify inadmissable combinations or opportunities to reduce your
    test cases, flag them and adjust your constraints or classes, then
    regenerate tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this process may require some iteration: you may want to use
the results of Step 3 to refine your inputs as generated from Steps 1
and 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this question, you must (1) describe your final equivalence classes
and constraints. (2) State how many tests TSL were initially generated
in Step 1 with no constraints and how many tests were finally generated
after iterating through the above steps. (3) list the final test frames
generated by the tool. (4) pick 3 test frames and create concrete test
cases for them (remember that test cases include input and output), (5)
Briefly (3-5 sentences), reflect on your experience in this process. Is
this something you would use again? Did it help you think about the
domain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hint: Note that this question does not have a single correct answer.
The goal is for you to think about criteria that make sense to partition
your domain into equivalence classes and what these equivalence classes
are. If you end up having too many test frames for such a simple problem
(e.g., 50-80), then perhaps think of further constraints that can help
you reduce this number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="question-2-6-marks"&gt;Question 2 (6 marks)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the following code, (a) provide a list of test cases that achieve
full branch coverage, keeping in mind that this is Java code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;{
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the same code, (b) provide a list of test cases that achieves full
statement coverage, but not full branch coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="question-3-7-marks"&gt;Question 3 (7 marks)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario:&lt;/strong&gt; A check-in machine is installed at an airport. A detailed
description of how to use this machine is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To use the check-in machine adhere to the following procedure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose to check in with your booking number or with your
    credit card:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(a) You have chosen to check in with your booking number. Enter your
    number and click "Continue".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;machine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;booking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;numbers&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;ii&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;If&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;correct&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;machine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;goes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;iii&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;If&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;correct&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;machine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;goes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;back&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;able&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;again&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(b) You have chosen to check in with your credit card. Put your card
    into the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;machine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;card&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;ii&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;If&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;card&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;accepted&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;machine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;goes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;iii&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;If&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;card&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;rejected&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;machine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;goes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will now be prompted for the number of luggage items you want to
    check in. When you have entered the number, you click "Continue" and
    the machine goes to 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will now be asked if you want to reserve a seat or change an
    existing seat reservation (if you have already reserved a seat)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(a) If you confirm, the machine goes to 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(b) If you do not confirm, the machine goes to 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You choose an available seat and click "Continue". The machine goes
    to 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your boarding card will be printed out along with the luggage tags.
    When you have taken the boarding card and luggage tags, the machine
    goes to 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machine wishes you an enjoyable flight, and goes back to 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During interaction with the machine, you always have the possibility to
click "Cancel". If you do so, the machine will immediately go back to
1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(a) [4 marks] Draw a finite state machine (a.k.a state transition
    diagram) that shows how the machine works. Make sure to clearly
    label your states (e.g., with numbers 1, 2 etc), such that you can
    refer to them in the next question. Also, beside the graph, write
    the total number of nodes and transitions in your graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(b) [1 mark] Write down a set of test cases, where each test case is a
    sequence of states (e.g., 1-&amp;gt;2-&amp;gt;3 etc), to achieve 100 percent
    state coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(c) [1 mark] What is the transition coverage of the test suite you
    created in (b)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(d) [1 mark] Is there any relationship between transition coverage and
    state coverage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="question-4-19-marks"&gt;Question 4 (19 marks)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the following method &lt;code&gt;isValidMove&lt;/code&gt; given below (&lt;em&gt;line numbers
shown for easier reference&lt;/em&gt;). It is based on the game
&lt;a href="https://bicyclecards.com/how-to-play/klondike/"&gt;Klondike&lt;/a&gt; where you
move cards around and the goal is to play move cards in way so that all
the cards end up in the suits where each of the four suits is a sequence
from Ace to King.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;static&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isValidMove&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;trim&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isEmpty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;trim&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isEmpty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Invalid: &amp;lt;from&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;to&amp;gt; both needs to be non-empty strings&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;equals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;stock&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isValidPileNumber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Valid: stock to pile&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;7.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;equals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;stock&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;SUITS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;contains&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;8.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Valid: stock to suit&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;9.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isValidPileNumber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;10.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isValidPileNumber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;SUITS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;contains&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;E&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;11.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;           &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Invalid: &amp;lt;to&amp;gt; value is invalid&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;12.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;13.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Valid: pile to (pile or suit)&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;14.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;15.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Invalid &amp;lt;from&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;to&amp;gt; value&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Helper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;variables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;methods&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;static&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;final&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Collection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;SUITS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Arrays&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;asList&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;s&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;d&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;h&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;c&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;static&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;boolean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isValidPileNumber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb nb-Type"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Integer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;parseInt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;trim&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;catch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;NumberFormatException&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="bp"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a) [4 marks] Draw a fully labelled control-flow graph for the method
    &lt;code&gt;isValidMove&lt;/code&gt;. You may use the labels A - E shown in the code to
    label predicates in the graph. For easier traceability for us when
    marking, please use the line numbers in the code to label nodes in
    your graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that the method &lt;code&gt;isValidPileNumber&lt;/code&gt; and the variable
&lt;code&gt;SUITS&lt;/code&gt; are provided to help you understand the logic, and they are not
be a part of the control-flow graph.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(b) [1 mark] Obtaining a 100% statement (a.k.a node) coverage requires
    (at least) six tests on this graph. Explain why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(c) [9 marks] Provide six tests (as calls to &lt;code&gt;isValidMove(from, to)&lt;/code&gt;)
    that satisfy 100% statement coverage on this graph. Make your tests
    short. You need to include assert statements in your test to
    indicate the expected output, or put a comment to clearly indicate
    what the expected output of this test is. &lt;strong&gt;For each test, indicate
    the path it covers.&lt;/strong&gt; For easier readability, please follow the
    following template for specifying your concrete tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;!--&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//ADD COVERED PATH AS A COMMENT&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;lt;EXPECTED&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;isValidMove&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;FROM&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;TO&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(d) [5 marks] Identify the conditions in this program and create a
    test suite with 100% MC/DC coverage. For each test case, provide
    concrete values for the &lt;code&gt;from&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;to&lt;/code&gt; parameters. You &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt;
    show your intermediate work and how you arrived to your answer.
    Final answers only will not get a grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hint: for each branch in the program, break it down into its
conditions, then create the MC/DC table for each branch predicate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2021, 2022 Dr. Sarah Nadi. Copyright 2023, 2024 Dr. Hazel Campbell. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="individual"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Individual Assignment 2: Testing with Mocks</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/individual/testing-mocks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-30:/individual/testing-mocks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Individual Assignment 2: Testing with Mocks&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#learning-goals"&gt;Learning Goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#task-unit-test-functionalities-of-a-desktop-application"&gt;Task: Unit test functionalities of a desktop application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#step-1-interesting-information"&gt;Step 1: Interesting Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#2-5-dont-exist-in-the-code-at-all-yet-you-need-to-add-the-functionality-yourself"&gt;2-5 don't exist in the code at all yet. You need to add the functionality yourself.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#step-2-robustness-tactic"&gt;Step 2: Robustness Tactic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#requirements-and-restrictions"&gt;Requirements and Restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading"&gt;Grading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#hints"&gt;Hints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most parts of software systems do not work in isolation and are difficult to test when the environment changes. Rather, these parts collaborate with multiple components to perform tasks that we want to implement and test. Various forms of mocks, stubs, fakes and other objects are used in many forms of testing to simulate the behavior of real objects that our implementation depends on to perform a specific task. One of the benefits of mocking dependencies is that we can focus on testing our implementation given that we have obtained the information that we expected from those dependencies. Furthermore, it allows to simulate error conditions in the environment and thus to test a system for robustness. In this assignment, you will test a desktop application by mocking a network service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="learning-goals"&gt;Learning Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply mocking testing tools and techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overcome mocking difficulties caused by conflicting tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit test functionalities of a desktop application that depends on a network service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design test cases to assess robustness of error handling implementations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github API &lt;a href="https://github-api.kohsuke.org/"&gt;https://github-api.kohsuke.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mockito API &lt;a href="https://site.mockito.org/"&gt;https://site.mockito.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EasyMock API &lt;a href="http://easymock.org/"&gt;http://easymock.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create your repository by accessing &lt;a href="https://classroom.github.com/a/P6dDMwhK"&gt;the GitHub classroom assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="task-unit-test-functionalities-of-a-desktop-application"&gt;Task: Unit test functionalities of a desktop application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are developing a GitHub dataminer in Java. Your application will automate a few data gathering tasks on GitHubt that may be of interest, such as finding out what day of the week (Monday, Tuesday, etc.) someone makes the most commits on. The current code is really basic and you are allowed to extend it. When developing your miner, you realize that interacting with the GitHub API is not simple as you expected. You need to obtain a token for interacting with the API. Also you do not want to run into API limits due to your tests running too often. You want to test whether your application could handle network connections gracefully. Primarily, you want to test the logic of your application and your error handling mechanisms, assuming you have already interacted with GitHub and received some response from the API. &lt;strong&gt;Your goal in this assignment is to mock the &lt;a href="https://github-api.kohsuke.org/"&gt;Java GitHub API&lt;/a&gt; dependency to test your implementation and its robustness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starter code contains some basic functionality for a GitHub miner. Extend the miner as described below and automate testing of the functionality of your miner without actually interacting with the real GitHub API. &lt;strong&gt;In the process, you may need to modify the existing source code to make the project testable (e.g., private methods cannot be tested and static method calls cannot be mocked).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="step-1-interesting-information"&gt;Step 1: Interesting Information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application must determine the following information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What day of the week you make the most git commits on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the average time between commits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long do issues on your repos stay open for, on average (consider only closed issues)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long do pull requests on your repos stay open for, on average&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many branches do your repos have, on average&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some code provided to help you get started with #1, but you should improve the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2-5-dont-exist-in-the-code-at-all-yet-you-need-to-add-the-functionality-yourself"&gt;2-5 don't exist in the code at all yet. You need to add the functionality yourself.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test each of these functionalities without actually communicating with the GitHub servers.
Your code should only communicate with the GitHub servers if Main is run normally, outside of tests. You do not need to test the Main function of the miner, just the functions that abstract the above mining functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="step-2-robustness-tactic"&gt;Step 2: Robustness Tactic&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above functionally, you need to improve the error handling mechanism of the application. Instead of the application crashing with some error if a task could not be completed, you need to retry 3 times before gracefully reporting an error message. You will need to test that this robustness tactic actually works as expected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend to add this robustness tactic to all interactions with the GitHub API, &lt;strong&gt;but for this assignment, it is sufficient to implement and test it for a single function of your choice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="deliverables"&gt;Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit your solution as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the code of implementation and tests regarding both steps should be in your GitHub classroom individual repo; tests should be executed automatically with Gradle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit a short report with explicit subsections (&amp;lt; 2 pages, hard limit) as a single PDF to eClass, describing the design decisions that you made to enable testing. Specifically: 
    a.  Describe which elements you chose to mock and why and where mocking was not necessary or useful.
    b.  Describe how you refactored the code to make it easier to test.
    c.  Explicitly mention which function you chose to implement robustness for and describe how you assessed that your testing w.r.t robustness is adequate.
    d.  If you had more time and resources, would you propose additional changes to make testing easier?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please indicate your repo url in your report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="requirements-and-restrictions"&gt;Requirements and Restrictions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must follow good testing practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must actually test the code that you are trying to test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should not mock your own code (with the exception of unavoidable wrapper classes: see Hints section below).&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should only be mocking the API provided by the "github-api" package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All methods and classes in your production code should be in use by the production code.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not add special methods, constructors, or classes that are only ever called by your testing code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grading"&gt;Grading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tota: 35 marks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 1 (15 marks, 3 for each functionality)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 2 (10 marks, 5 for adding robustness + 5 for testing it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report (10 marks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hints"&gt;Hints&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to change private visibility to protected visibility in order to access them from your testing code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mockito and github-api both use Java bytecode manipulation. Mockito does this to help inject dependencies. However, this can come into conflict with methods in the github-api that are decorated with &lt;code&gt;@WithBridgeMethods&lt;/code&gt;. One example is the &lt;code&gt;GHIssue.comment&lt;/code&gt; method. This can result in an error like &lt;code&gt;Date cannot be returned by getCreatedAt() getCreatedAt() should return String&lt;/code&gt;. This error message doesn't really make sense because the application bytecode was manipulated &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; being compiled. In order to solve this, you will need to create a wrapper for &lt;code&gt;GHIssue&lt;/code&gt;, use the wrapper in the production code, and then mock the wrapper instead of the wrapper class from github-api in the test code. You will also need to do this for any other methods that are decorated with &lt;code&gt;@WithBridgeMethods&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hub4j/github-api/tree/main/src/main/java/org/kohsuke/github"&gt;github-api code&lt;/a&gt;. So if you get a strange error with impossible types, check the code of github-api to see if it uses such a decorator, and add a wrapper class as needed. This is not the only way to solve this problem, but it's the easiest way we've found so far. &lt;em&gt;Wrapper classes shouldn't do anything but just call the class they are wrapping.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually you should avoid modifying the production code to add wrappers that are only necessary for the test code to work. However, in this case it is unavoidable becuase the methods mockito and the github-api code use are in conflict. Similar conflicts can also arise in other programming languages such as Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that there are many different ways to solve everything in this assignment. For example, mockito has &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; decorators that can make your code a lot cleaner than the provided sample code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the &lt;code&gt;try (MockedConstrcution&lt;/code&gt; pattern to intercept any constructor. This is using a Java feature called &lt;a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/essential/exceptions/tryResourceClose.html"&gt;try-with-resources&lt;/a&gt;. But its not necessary to do unless the "new" you're trying to intercept is in the production code (or somewhere inside of github-api). For any constructors called in the testing code, you can just &lt;code&gt;mock(Whatever.class)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2021, 2022 Dr. Sarah Nadi. Copyright 2023, 2024 Dr. Hazel Campbell. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="individual"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Course Outline Winter 2024</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/outline.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/outline.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;University of Alberta &lt;br&gt; CMPUT 402/501 - Software Quality &lt;br&gt; LEC-B1 &lt;br&gt; Winter 2024&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;University of Alberta &lt;br&gt; CMPUT 402/501 - Software Quality &lt;br&gt; LEC-B1 &lt;br&gt; Winter 2024&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eClass Page&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://eclass.srv.ualberta.ca/course/view.php?id=95226"&gt;https://eclass.srv.ualberta.ca/course/view.php?id=95226&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home Page&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/"&gt;https://cmput402.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#lecture"&gt;Lecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#labs"&gt;Labs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#contact-information"&gt;Contact Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#course-content"&gt;Course Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#learning-resources"&gt;Learning Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#on-line-homework-disclaimer"&gt;On-Line Homework Disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#academic-success-centre"&gt;Academic Success Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grade-evaluation"&gt;Grade Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#group-assignments"&gt;Group Assignments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#midterm-exams"&gt;Midterm Exams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#participation"&gt;Participation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#letter-grades"&gt;Letter Grades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#statement-of-expectations-for-ai-use"&gt;Statement of Expectations for AI Use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#re-evaluation-of-term-work"&gt;Re-Evaluation of Term Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#re-examination"&gt;Re-examination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#past-or-representative-evaluative-material"&gt;Past or Representative evaluative Material&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#late-policy"&gt;Late Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#missed-term-work"&gt;Missed Term Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#remote-delivery-considerations"&gt;Remote Delivery Considerations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#recordings-of-synchronous-activities"&gt;Recordings of Synchronous Activities:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#in-case-of-emergency"&gt;In Case of Emergency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#student-responsibilities"&gt;Student Responsibilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#academic-integrity-and-student-conduct"&gt;Academic Integrity and Student Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#appropriate-collaboration-midterm-exams"&gt;Appropriate Collaboration: Midterm Exams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#apropriate-collaboration-quizzes-participation"&gt;Apropriate Collaboration: Quizzes &amp;amp; Participation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#appropriate-collaboration-assignments"&gt;Appropriate Collaboration: Assignments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#apropriate-collaboration-group-assignments"&gt;Apropriate Collaboration (Group Assignments)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#appropriate-collaboration-general"&gt;Appropriate Collaboration: General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#exam-conduct"&gt;Exam Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#lecture-conduct"&gt;Lecture Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#students-eligible-for-accessibility-related-accommodations"&gt;Students Eligible for Accessibility-Related Accommodations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#required-equipment"&gt;Required Equipment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#on-campus-computer-labs"&gt;On-Campus Computer Labs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#recording-andor-distribution-of-course-materials"&gt;Recording and/or Distribution of Course Materials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#learning-and-working-environment"&gt;Learning and Working Environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#feeling-stressed-anxious-or-upset"&gt;Feeling Stressed, Anxious, or Upset?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#additional-information"&gt;Additional Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#update-history"&gt;Update History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lecture"&gt;Lecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3:30 to 4:50 PM, &lt;a href="http://www.campusmap.ualberta.ca/?b=nre"&gt;NRE&lt;/a&gt; 2-003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hybrid Synchronous. Recordings will not be available without an approved excuse or registered accommodations. You must attend live.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will be required to attend in person for some lectures/labs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="labs"&gt;Labs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H01: Monday, 5:00PM to 7:50PM, NRE 2-003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H02: Wednesday, 5:00PM to 7:50PM, NRE 1-143&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/labs.html"&gt;Lab Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="contact-information"&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lecturer: Dr. Hazel Victoria Campbell&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E-mail: &lt;a href="mailto:hazel.campbell@ualberta.ca"&gt;hazel.campbell@ualberta.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.campusmap.ualberta.ca/?b=ath"&gt;ATH&lt;/a&gt; 4-05&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office hours (ATH 4-05):&lt;/strong&gt; Monday, Wednesday, Friday 2:10-2:50PM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office hours (Zoom):&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(email to make an appointment)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TA Contact Info and Office hours is on eClass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="course-content"&gt;Course Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Students will learn about the best processes to follow to produce better
quality software that is also more maintainable. The course will discuss
different types of tests, automated quality assurance tools and pipelines,
and quality models. The course is geared towards practicing all covered
concepts using state-of-the-art tools with lots of hands-on projects and
assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Pre-requisites:&lt;/strong&gt; CMPUT 301 (includes knowledge of Java, design patterns, basic unit testing, build systems, basic software engineering principles, previous knowledge working on medium sized systems)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Objectives and Expected Learning Outcomes:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand which testing or code analysis strategies can catch a given
type of software bug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up and use automated continuous integration and deployment services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to contribute quality improvements to an existing project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Topics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous integration and deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static analysis tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security, safety, and performance quality aspects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Schedule and Assigned Readings:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weekly topic schedule is likely to be updated during the term; please see &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1nI9E-naS2anf7boJF33eY43MlRjv1f0ymMJ3LdIinss/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;the live version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="learning-resources"&gt;Learning Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Texbook:&lt;/strong&gt; There is no required text book for this course.
Various related resources and readings will be provided by the instructor
on eClass throughout the course.
If you would like to get a comprehensive foundation in software testing, you
may want to check out the &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Software Testing&lt;/em&gt; book by Paul
Ammann and Jeff Offutt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended or Optional Learning Resources&lt;/strong&gt;: Additional resources may be provided by links from this site or the course eClass page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Fees&lt;/strong&gt;: Students may be required to purchase online hosting if there are technical difficulties. We are planning to provide free hosing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="on-line-homework-disclaimer"&gt;On-Line Homework Disclaimer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On-line homework is a component of this course and is provided by a third-party company.  Please be aware that this company will be storing assessment information that may be associated with you.  As a way to protect your personal information, you will invent or you will be assigned a random ID to enter into the system. Only the random ID, performance on the on-line homework and the affiliation to the University of Alberta for this random ID will be conveyed to the company.  You are not required to provide any additional personal information to this company.  If you have any concerns about this, please contact the instructor of the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration in the system and any monetary transactions are of your own accord and not the responsibility of the University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students should be mindful of protecting their personal information and should be aware of how their personal information might be used and/or shared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students MUST NOT use their @ualberta email address or CCID to register into the system and instead should use a non-identifying email address or account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id="academic-success-centre"&gt;Academic Success Centre&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-success-centre/index.html"&gt;Academic Success Centre&lt;/a&gt; provides professional academic support to help students strengthen their academic skills and achieve their academic goals. Individual advising, appointments, and group workshops are available year round in the areas of Accessibility, Communication, Learning, and Writing Resources. Modest fees apply for some services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grade-evaluation"&gt;Grade Evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the last column, it shows collaboration models for each unit of work. These styles are better described on the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/department-course-policies.html"&gt;CS course policy page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Assesment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;402 Wt&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;501 Wt&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Collaboration&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Midterm 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Midterm 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Individual Assignment 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Individual Assignment 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Individual Assignment 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group Project 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teamwork&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group Project 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teamwork&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group Project 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teamwork&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group Project 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teamwork&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group Project 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teamwork&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Participation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In-Class Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Extra Credit*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;+1%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;+1%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no final exam for this course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades are unofficial until approved by the Department and/or Faculty offering the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Extra credit is recieved by submitting a helpfull PR to the website repo and emailing the course instructor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="group-assignments"&gt;Group Assignments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group members for group projects will be randomly assigned. Groups for the group projects remain the same throughout the term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For group projects, graduate students will work in groups of up to 2 while undergraduate students will work in groups of up to 4 students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weight for each group project differs (proportional to required effort).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For any group work, unless otherwise explicitly specified in the assignment description, all group members receive the same grade.
All group work comes with a peer evaluation of group member contributions.
If concerned, the course staff reserve the right to further investigate each group member’s contributions, including an oral examination component, and re-assign grades accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="midterm-exams"&gt;Midterm Exams&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exams will be in-person during the lecture period. Your photo ID will be
required to verify your identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="participation"&gt;Participation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMPUT 402: Participation marks will be marked out of 5 points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMPUT 501: Participation marks will be marked out of 10 points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At most one point can be earned per lecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A point can be earned by answering an instructor's question during class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A point can be earned by asking a thoughtful question about the course material during class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Points can be earned either in-person or by participating over Zoom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifically no points will be awarded for asking/answering questions about the course itself, such as grades, submission requirements, due dates, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional opportunities may be added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="letter-grades"&gt;Letter Grades&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no fixed formula for translating your composite marks into a final grade.&lt;/strong&gt; The final letter grade will be assigned based on how your course percentage represents mastery of the course material according to the University of Alberta grading system guidelines. The guidelines state that "Grades reflect judgements of student achievement made by instructors and must correspond to the associated descriptor. These judgements are based on a combination of absolute achievement and relative performance in a class. " This quote and further information about the grading system including the descriptors can be found in the &lt;a href="http://www.registrar.ualberta.ca/calendar/Regulations-and-Information/Academic-Regulation/23.4.html#23.4"&gt;University Calendar&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/department-course-policies.html"&gt;CS Department policies&lt;/a&gt; about grading also apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How many % do I need in the course to get an A? To get a B? To get a C?&lt;/strong&gt; We do not use pre-defined percentages of your final mark to compute your final grade, but instead use our judgement of how your final percentage indicates the level of mastery in the table above for an A, B, C, D+. This is done at the end of the semester. A 50% or better final grade usually earns at least a D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the standard system in use by most Computing Science courses at the University of Alberta. However, it may not be what you are used to from other institutions.
The department of Computing Science believes this produces a fair evaluation and our extensive experience supports this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Descriptor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Interpretation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Excellent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Good&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Like an A, but not consistent over time, or weak in a specific area.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Satisfactory&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Understand the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations on own and to more complex situations with hints, evidence that the material has changed the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Poor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Understand some of the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations but often needs assistance, evidence that the material has had some change on the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Minimal Pass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shows some understanding of parts of the material, cannot apply it without some direction, little evidence that the material has changed the way of thinking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Failure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Little evidence of understanding of even the surface issues, poor analysis and synthesis, inability to apply the material.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end of the semester, the minimum overall percentage demonstrates "Excellent" in the table above will be the minimum percentage for an A-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates "Good" will be the minimum percentage for a B-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates "Satisfactory" will be the minimum percentage for a C-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates "Poor" will be the minimum percentage for a D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything over 50% is usually at least a D, sometimes it is higher than a D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every semester contains different material, since every semester we try to improve the course, and we also need to constantly create new questions and assignments to mitigate cheating.
Thus, the breakpoints change from semester to semester.
However, these changes do not depend on the class average, they depend on the percentage that demonstrates different levels in the table above!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/grade_letters.html"&gt;Percentages and Letter Grades explanation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="statement-of-expectations-for-ai-use"&gt;Statement of Expectations for AI Use&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You MUST not submit work by Chat GPT as your own, that is plagiarism.&lt;/strong&gt; This also applies to other "AI" and Generative Models: Lex.page, DALL-E2, Google BARD, Microsoft Bing, and others. If you use ChatGPT you must cite it. This includes the Entity, Resource, Subject, and Date. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// The following function from Microsoft, Bing, &amp;quot;How do I write a merge sort in JavaScript?&amp;quot;, 2023-08-31&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;mergeSort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use ChatGPT &lt;strong&gt;you must cite it&lt;/strong&gt;, but it's probably better to Google what it tells you and find a real citation because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChatGPT is wrong a lot.&lt;/strong&gt; It does not understand computer science. It understands how to form sentences and paragraphs well enough to be convincing, but it doesn't actually understand what anything it is saying means. When it has the choice between two sentences, with opposite meanings, it will pick the sentence that looks more like English it has seen, it does not pick the one that is most correct. This means you need to double-check that what it tells you is actually correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stackoverflow is always a better resource than Large Language Models such as ChatGPT&lt;/strong&gt;, but of course if you use code from Stackoverflow or any other website, &lt;strong&gt;you must cite it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT and similar services are recording everything you tell it, and tracking you.
Using ChatGPT/Bing/Bard etc. they are recording everything you say and how the LLM responds
to you. There is no privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ChatGPT example from CMPUT 229:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Me: "What is the difference between the b and j pseudoinstruction in RISC-V?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ChatGPT: "... The b instruction is actually a shorthand for the more general beq (branch if equal) instruction, which compares two registers and branches if they are equal. However, &amp;gt; &amp;gt; in the case of b, one of the registers is always x0 (the zero register), so the comparison &amp;gt; is always false, effectively causing an unconditional jump. ...the key difference between b &amp;gt; and j is that b is a relative branch instruction that jumps to a location within a limited range, while j is an absolute jump instruction that can jump to any address within the range of the program counter."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 3 problems with this answer:&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b is not shorthand for beq: RARS replaces it with jal -- the actual replacement depends on the assembler used and the situation it is used in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This also makes ChatGPT's conclusion about relative limited range jumps and absolute jumps wrong. All jumps and branches in RISC-V are relative, short range jumps except jalr. RARS also (at least in every case I've seen) translates j to jal, not jalr, and jal is also a short-range, relative jump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If b gets translated to beq x0, Y, label then what guarantees that the other register isn't also zero? The comparison with beq x0, Y cannot always be false, despite what ChatGPT claimed. This really doesn't make any sense. It would make more sense for it to be translated to bne x0, x0, label   ... but that's the opposite instruction of what ChatGPT claimed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="re-evaluation-of-term-work"&gt;Re-Evaluation of Term Work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-Evaluation of Term Work follows the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/department-course-policies.html"&gt;Computing Science department course policies&lt;/a&gt;. Any questions or concerns about marks on a particular assignment must be brought to the attention of the instructor &lt;em&gt;(not a TA)&lt;/em&gt; within 10 days of its return date. After that, we will not consider remarking or re-evaluating the work. So do not expect anyone to re-evaluate all the work you did all term long in the hopes of getting a higher final grade. However, clerical errors such as incorrectly computing or recording a mark may be raised at any time prior to 2 working days following the final exam. It is the student's responsibility to confirm that their term work has been recorded properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="re-examination"&gt;Re-examination&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course does not have a final examination: there is no possibility of a re-examination in this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--A student who writes the final examination and fails the course may apply for a re-examination.  Re-examinations are rarely granted in the Faculty of Science.  Re-examinations are governed by [university-wide Academic Regulations](https://calendar.ualberta.ca/content.php?catoid=39&amp;navoid=12216#reexaminations) and [Faculty of Science Academic Regulations](https://calendar.ualberta.ca/content.php?catoid=39&amp;navoid=12231#reexamination). Misrepresentation of Facts to gain a re-examination is a serious breach of the Code of Student Behaviour.--&gt;

&lt;h4 id="past-or-representative-evaluative-material"&gt;Past or Representative evaluative Material&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will be posted on eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="late-policy"&gt;Late Policy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely no late work will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="missed-term-work"&gt;Missed Term Work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missed Term Work or Final Exam Due to Non-medical Protected Grounds&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., religious beliefs): When a term assessment or final exam presents a conflict based on &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-success-centre/accessibility-resources/register/eligibility.html"&gt;non-medical protected grounds&lt;/a&gt;, students must apply to the Academic Success Centre for accommodations via their &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-success-centre/accessibility-resources/register/index.html"&gt;Register for Accommodations&lt;/a&gt; website. Students can review their eligibility and choose the application process specific for &lt;em&gt;Accommodations Based on Non-medical Protected Grounds&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is imperative that students review the dates of all course assessments upon receipt of the course outline, and apply &lt;strong&gt;AS SOON AS POSSIBLE&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure the timely application of the accommodation. Students who apply later in the term may experience unavoidable delays in the processing of the application, which can affect the accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missed Term Work: Assignments, Labs, Projects, Midterm Exams&lt;/strong&gt;: A student who cannot complete a course component (except the final exam, see the next section) due to incapacitating illness, severe domestic affliction or other compelling reasons must contact the instructor within two working days of missing the assessment, or as soon as possible, to request an excused absence. If an excused absence is granted, then weight will be transferred to other course components. An excused absence is a privilege and not a right. There is no guarantee that an absence will be excused. Misrepresentation of facts to gain an excused absence is a serious breach of the Code of Student Behaviour. In all cases, instructors may request adequate documentation to substantiate the reason for the absence at their discretion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missed Term Work: Participation&lt;/strong&gt;: One third (rounded down) of the lowest marks for participation will be dropped when calculating the course mark. No late participation will be accepted.
Failure to participate on time for any reason will result in a mark of zero. Please note that you can miss &lt;strong&gt;one third&lt;/strong&gt; of the participation opportunities without penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deferred Final Examination&lt;/strong&gt;: This course does not have a final examination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--**Deferred Final Examination**: A student who cannot write the final examination due to incapacitating illness, severe domestic affliction or other compelling reasons can apply for a deferred final examination. Such an application must be made to the student’s Faculty office within two working days of the missed examination and must be supported by appropriate documentation or a Statutory Declaration (see calendar on [Attendance](https://calendar.ualberta.ca/content.php?catoid=39&amp;navoid=12216#attendance)). Deferred examinations are a privilege and not a right; there is no guarantee that a deferred examination will be granted. The Faculty may deny deferral requests in cases where less than 50% of term work has been completed. Misrepresentation of facts to gain a deferred examination is a serious breach of the Code of Student Behaviour. --&gt;

&lt;h3 id="remote-delivery-considerations"&gt;Remote Delivery Considerations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise instructed by an instructor, &lt;strong&gt;this course requires attendance in-person or via Zoom during the scheduled lectures and labs.&lt;/strong&gt; Some lectures or labs require in-person attendance, like the last lab for presentations, and for exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Lectures&lt;/strong&gt; will be given in &lt;strong&gt;hybrid&lt;/strong&gt; format. The lecture will be given in the lecture room on campus. At the same time, the lecture will also be streamed via Zoom and a recording of the lecture content will be made.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lecture recordings will be available &lt;strong&gt;on request only&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want a lecture recording, you must contact the instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students are expected to attend during the lecture either on Zoom or in-person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentations and Guest Lectures&lt;/strong&gt; will be given &lt;strong&gt;in-person only.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most lab sessions&lt;/strong&gt; will be available in a hybrid format: you may attend either in-person or online.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For group projects, the entire group must be online, or the entire group must be in-person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;group presentation&lt;/strong&gt;, you must present &lt;strong&gt;in-person&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exams&lt;/strong&gt; must be taken &lt;strong&gt;in-person&lt;/strong&gt;. They will not be online. You must bring your Student ID (One Card).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled office hours&lt;/strong&gt; will be available &lt;strong&gt;in-person&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional &lt;strong&gt;office appointments&lt;/strong&gt; will be conducted &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt; (usually Zoom, maybe Google Meet). Email the instructor to set up an appointment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="recordings-of-synchronous-activities"&gt;Recordings of Synchronous Activities:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please note that class times for this course will be recorded. Recordings of this course will be used for the purposes of accommodating students who experienced illness, domestic affliction, improving accessibility and will be disclosed to other students enrolled in this section of the class, teaching assistants, university officials, and other professors in the CS department.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students have the right to not participate in the recording and are advised to turn off their cameras and audio prior to recording; they can still participate through text-based chat. It is recommended that students remove all identifiable and personal belongings from the space in which they will be participating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recordings will be kept until the end of the semester and accessible by eClass, Google Drive, or Zoom Cloud Storage. Please direct any questions about this collection to the instructor of this course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recordings will be made available only to students who are unable to attend in person or via Zoom at the time of the leture due to incapacitating illness, severe domestic affliction, duty to accommodate or other compelling reasons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="in-case-of-emergency"&gt;In Case of Emergency&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;in the case that some parts of the class are moved on-line,&lt;/strong&gt; for example due to an emergency the following will apply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology for Remote Learning: To successfully participate in remote learning in this course, it is recommended that students have access to a computer with an internet connection that can support the tools and technologies the University uses to deliver content, engage with instructors, TAs, and fellow students, and facilitate assessment and examinations. Please refer to Technology for Remote Learning - For Students for details. If you encounter difficulty meeting the technology recommendations, please email the Dean of Students Office (dosdean@ualberta.ca) directly to explore options and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact the instructor by the add/drop deadline if you do not have access to the minimum technology recommended. The instructor will make arrangements for accommodating students who contact the instructor before this date. Failure to do so may result in a zero in any assessment that depends on the minimum technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote Proctoring Consideration: We may use a remote proctoring service for exams. Your computer and environment may be monitored during exams. 
You should arrange for a place to write timed exams without interruption. 
Tablets and mobile devices are incompatible with remote proctoring services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home-Based Lab Activities: As part of the learning experience in this course, you will be required to undertake certain activities in or around your place of residence. To ensure that you undertake the activity safely and fully informed of the risks, please review the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/finance-procurement-planning/media-library/insurance-risk-assessment/remote-learning-lab-based-assignment-information-advisory.pdf"&gt;University of Alberta’s Remote Learning Lab-Based Assignment Information Advisory&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions or concerns, contact your instructor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Resources for Remote Learning: Online learning may be new to you. Check out tips for success and find out more about online learning on the &lt;a href="http://ualberta.ca/campus-life/index.html"&gt;Campus Life&lt;/a&gt; page, and specifically on the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-success-centre/resources/index.html"&gt;Academic Skills Online &amp;amp; Remote Delivery Resources&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id="student-responsibilities"&gt;Student Responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id="academic-integrity-and-student-conduct"&gt;Academic Integrity and Student Conduct&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Alberta is committed to the highest standards of academic integrity and honesty, as well as maintaining a learning environment that fosters the safety, security, and the inherent dignity of each member of the community, ensuring students conduct themselves accordingly. Students are expected to be familiar with the standards of academic honesty and appropriate student conduct, and to uphold the policies of the University in this respect. Students are particularly urged to familiarize themselves with the provisions of the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/governance/resources/policies-standards-and-codes-of-conduct/code-of-student-behaviour.html"&gt;Code of Student Behaviour&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://policiesonline.ualberta.ca/PoliciesProcedures/Policies/Student-Conduct-Policy.pdf#search=Student%20Conduct%20Policy"&gt;Student Conduct Policy&lt;/a&gt;, and avoid any behaviour that could potentially result in suspicions of academic misconduct (e.g., cheating, plagiarism, misrepresentation of facts) and non-academic misconduct (e.g., discrimination, harassment, physical assault). Academic and non-academic misconduct are taken very seriously and can result in suspension or expulsion from the University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to consult the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-resources/academic-integrity"&gt;Academic Integrity website &lt;/a&gt;for clarification on the various academic offences. All forms of academic dishonesty are unacceptable at the University. Any suspected academic offence in this course will be reported to the College of Natural and Applied Sciences. Suspected cases of non-academic misconduct will be reported to the Dean of Students. The College, the Faculty of Science, and the Dean of Students are committed to student rights and responsibilities, and adhere to due process and administrative fairness, as outlined in the Code of Student Behaviour and the Student Conduct Policy. Anyone who is found in violation is likely to receive a sanction. Typical sanctions for academic misconduct include conduct probation, a mark reduction or a mark of 0 on an assessment, a grade reduction or a grade of F in a course, a remark on the transcript, and a recommendation for suspension or expulsion. Sanctions for non-academic misconduct include conduct conditions, fines, suspension of essential or non-essential University services and resources, and suspension or expulsion from the University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="appropriate-collaboration-midterm-exams"&gt;Appropriate Collaboration: Midterm Exams&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midterm Exams are confidential. No discussion of the contents of the exam is permitted except with instructors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="apropriate-collaboration-quizzes-participation"&gt;Apropriate Collaboration: Quizzes &amp;amp; Participation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quizzes and Participation are &lt;strong&gt;Solo Effort&lt;/strong&gt; and must be completed by the student registered in the course without external assistance from any individual or organization. &lt;em&gt;Students may only submit work authored by themselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="appropriate-collaboration-assignments"&gt;Appropriate Collaboration: Assignments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are not permitted to copy solutions on homework assignments. Here are some tips to avoid copying on assignments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not write down something that you cannot explain to your instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not copy and paste something that you cannot explain to your instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not copy and paste something without citing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you are helping other students, avoid showing them your work directly. Instead, explain your solution verbally in terms of ideas instead of reading them your code. Students whose work is copied also receive academic sanctions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find yourself reading another student's solution, do not write anything down. Once you understand how to solve the problem, remove the other person's work from your sight and then write up the solution to the question yourself. Looking back and forth between someone else's paper and your own paper is copying and will result in academic sanctions for both you and your fellow student.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the instructor or TA writes down part of a solution in order to help explain it to you or the class, you cannot copy it and hand it in for credit.
Treat it the same way you would treat another student's work with respect to copying, that is, remove the explanation from your sight and then write up the solution yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is often more than one way to solve a problem. Choose the method that makes the most sense to you rather than the method that other students happen to use. If none of the ideas in your solution are your own, there is a good chance it will be flagged as copying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each student must be able to verbally describe their exam answers and code, line by line, to a professor or TA, if asked to do so. Your mark may be reduced if you aren't able to explain your own work satisfactorily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For some of the substantial programming assignments and homework questions, students may discuss the concepts covered by the assignment with other students registered in the course as long as they do not share actual solutions or programming code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you include code or ideas from someone who isn't you (including from an Generative AI or LLM) you must cite it. Here is an example of an appropriate citation:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# The following function from Django Software Foundation and contributors, &amp;quot;Writing your first Django app, part 2&amp;quot;, 2024-01-05&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;Choice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;question&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ForeignKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Question&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;on_delete&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;CASCADE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;choice_text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;CharField&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;max_length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;votes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;IntegerField&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For programming assignments software tools are used to detect plagiarism. When the software tools indicate that there is similarity between two submissions, the submissions are reviewed by the instructor or teaching assistant. If the possibility that the standards for academic honesty were violated is confirmed, an investigation is started. Eventually the submitted solutions may be forwarded to the Faculty of Science Associate Dean of Students for further investigation and eventual sanctions. Submissions will be retained for future comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="apropriate-collaboration-group-assignments"&gt;Apropriate Collaboration (Group Assignments)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As long as you are a part of a group, you are responsible for everything in the group project, whether or not you participated in every component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A group may only submit work authored by group members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No collaboration between groups is allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="appropriate-collaboration-general"&gt;Appropriate Collaboration: General&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-resources/academic-integrity/collaboration.html"&gt;More information about appropriate collaboration.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/department-course-policies.html"&gt;CS Department Course Policies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="exam-conduct"&gt;Exam Conduct&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are not on the class list, you may not write the examination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your student photo I.D. is required at exams to verify your identity.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will not be allowed to begin an examination after it has been in progress for 30 minutes.  Students must remain in the exam room until at least 30 minutes has elapsed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not start the test or open the test booklet until instructed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All electronic devices must be turned off and stored in your bags. The only permitted electronics are those being used for accessibility or accomodations. This includes calculators, smart watches, and headphones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If noise distracts you, bring ear plugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must leave your bag at the front of the classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not write down letters for multiple-choice questions, circle your answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are not allowed to keep any part of the exam, scratch paper, or your notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must sign the class list and the exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="lecture-conduct"&gt;Lecture Conduct&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cell phone audio/ringers are to be turned off during lectures, labs and seminars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cell phone and computer use during the lecture is only permitted for participation, note-taking, and other activities directly related to the lecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="students-eligible-for-accessibility-related-accommodations"&gt;Students Eligible for Accessibility-Related Accommodations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In accordance with the University of Alberta’s &lt;a href="https://policiesonline.ualberta.ca/PoliciesProcedures/Policies/Discrimination-Harassment-and-Duty-to-Accommodate-Policy.pdf"&gt;Discrimination, Harassment, and Duty to Accommodate&lt;/a&gt; policy, accommodation support is available to eligible students who encounter limitations or restrictions to their ability to perform the daily activities necessary to pursue studies at a post-secondary level due to medical conditions and/or non-medical protected grounds. Accommodations are coordinated through the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-success-centre/index.html"&gt;Academic Success Centre&lt;/a&gt;, and students can learn more about eligibility on the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/academic-success-centre/accessibility-resources/register/index.html"&gt;Register for Accommodations website&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended that students apply as early as possible in order to ensure sufficient time to complete accommodation registration and coordination. Students are advised to review and adhere to published deadlines for accommodation approval and for specific accommodation requests (e.g., exam registration submission deadlines). Students who request accommodations less than a month in advance of the academic term for which they require accommodations may experience unavoidable delays or consequences in their academic programs, and may need to consider alternative academic schedules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="required-equipment"&gt;Required Equipment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tablet, phone, or other mobile device will NOT work for this course. You need a laptop or desktop computer, running Windows, Mac OS X/11+, or Linux. A Chromebook probably will not work unless it can run Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="on-campus-computer-labs"&gt;On-Campus Computer Labs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/undergraduate-conditions-of-use.html"&gt;Undergraduate Conditions of Use&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/lab-policies.html"&gt;Lab Policies&lt;/a&gt; for information about undergraduate labs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="recording-andor-distribution-of-course-materials"&gt;Recording and/or Distribution of Course Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio or video recording, digital or otherwise, of lectures, labs, seminars or any other teaching environment by students is allowed only with the prior written consent of the instructor or as a part of an approved accommodation plan. Student or instructor content, digital or otherwise, created and/or used within the context of the course is to be used solely for personal study, and is not to be used or distributed for any other purpose without prior written consent from the content author(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="learning-and-working-environment"&gt;Learning and Working Environment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Faculty of Science is committed to ensuring that all students, faculty and staff are able to work and study in an environment that is safe and free from discrimination, harassment, and violence of any kind. It does not tolerate behaviour that undermines that environment. This includes virtual environments and platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are experiencing harassment, discrimination, fraud, theft or any other issue and would like to get confidential advice, please contact any of these campus services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/provost/portfolio/office-of-safe-disclosure-human-rights/index.html"&gt;Office of Safe Disclosure &amp;amp; Human Rights&lt;/a&gt;: A safe, neutral and confidential space to disclose concerns about how the University of Alberta policies, procedures or ethical standards are being applied. They provide strategic advice and referral on matters such as discrimination, harassment, duty to accommodate and wrong-doings. Disclosures can be made in person or online using the &lt;a href="https://ualberta-gme-advocate.symplicity.com/titleix_report/index.php"&gt;Online Reporting Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/protective-services"&gt;University of Alberta Protective Services&lt;/a&gt;: Peace officers dedicated to ensuring the safety and security of U of A campuses and community. Staff or students can contact UAPS to make a report if they feel unsafe, threatened, or targeted on campus or by another member of the university community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/ombuds/index.html"&gt;Office of the Student Ombuds&lt;/a&gt;: A confidential and free service that strives to ensure that university processes related to students operate as fairly as possible. They offer information, advice, and support to students, faculty, and staff as they deal with academic, discipline, interpersonal, and financial issues related to student programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/dean-of-students/index.html"&gt;Office of the Dean of Students&lt;/a&gt;: They can assist students in navigating services to ensure they receive appropriate and timely resources. For students who are unsure of the support they may need, are concerned about how to access services on campus, or feel like they may need interim support while you wait to access a service, the Dean of Students office is here to help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="feeling-stressed-anxious-or-upset"&gt;Feeling Stressed, Anxious, or Upset?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's normal for us to have different mental health experiences throughout the year. Know that there are people who want to help. You can reach out to your friends and access a variety of supports available on and off campus at the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/need-help-now.html"&gt;Need Help Now&lt;/a&gt; webpage or by calling the 24-hour Distress Line: 780-482-4357 (HELP). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Student Self-Care Guide&lt;/strong&gt;: 
This &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1t5fqgXCG369tt5hDxrzQuvlTdy2W46RB/view?usp=sharing"&gt;Self-Care Guide&lt;/a&gt;, originally designed by the Faculty of Native Studies, has broader application for use during students’ learning. It provides some ideas and strategies to consider that can help navigate emotionally challenging or triggering material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="additional-information"&gt;Additional Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy about course outlines can be found in &lt;a href="https://calendar.ualberta.ca/content.php?catoid=39&amp;amp;navoid=12216#course-requirements-evaluation-procedures-and-grading"&gt;Course Requirements, Evaluations Procedures and Grading&lt;/a&gt; of the University Calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policies applicable to CS Department courses can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/department-course-policies.html"&gt;Department Course Policies&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Land Acknowledgement&lt;/strong&gt;:
The University of Alberta respectfully acknowledges that we are situated on Treaty 6 territory, traditional lands of First Nations and Métis people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the significance of this land acknowledgement, please read &lt;a href="https://toronto.citynews.ca/2022/06/24/what-are-land-acknowledgements-and-why-do-they-matter/"&gt;this useful article&lt;/a&gt; and associated links to more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: 
Any typographical errors in this Course Outline are subject to change and will be announced in class. The date of the final examination is set by the Registrar and takes precedence over the final examination date reported in this syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyright&lt;/strong&gt;:
Dr. Hazel Campbell, Department of Computing Science, Faculty of Science, University of Alberta (2023, 2024).
Dr. Abram Hindle, Department of Computing Science, Faculty of Science, University of Alberta (2023).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="update-history"&gt;Update History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024-01-08: Initial version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="outline"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category><category term="contact"></category></entry><entry><title>Grade Letters</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/grade_letters.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/grade_letters.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Grading System, Percentages and Letters, Breakpoint Calculation&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-system-percentages-and-letters"&gt;Grading System: Percentages and Letters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#breakpoint-calculations-and-examples"&gt;Breakpoint Calculations and Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grading-system-percentages-and-letters"&gt;Grading System: Percentages and Letters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not use pre-defined percentages of your final mark to compute your final grade, but instead use our judgement of how your final percentage indicates the level of mastery in the table below for an A, B, C, D+. This is done after the final exam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the standard system in use by most Computing Science courses at the University of Alberta. However, it may not be what you are used to from other institutions.
The department of Computing Science believes this produces a fair evaluation and our extensive experience supports this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: center;"&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: center;"&gt;Descriptor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Interpretation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;A+&lt;br&gt;A&lt;br&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Excellent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;B+&lt;br&gt;B&lt;br&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Good&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Like an A, but not consistent over time, or weak in a specific area.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;C+&lt;br&gt;C&lt;br&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Satisfactory&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Understand the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations on own and to more complex situations with hints, evidence that the material has changed the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Poor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Understand some of the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations but often needs assistance, evidence that the material has had some change on the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Minimal&lt;br&gt;Pass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Shows some understanding of parts of the material, cannot apply it without some direction, little evidence that the material has changed the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Failure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Little evidence of understanding of even the surface issues, poor analysis and synthesis, inability to apply the material.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find a copy of this table on the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/department-course-policies.html"&gt;Department Course Policies&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The table listed above is used to translate the final percentage in the course to a letter grade by using grade breakpoints after the final exam.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is done by using &lt;em&gt;breakpoints&lt;/em&gt;: each letter grade is given a minimum percentage required to get that letter grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction."&lt;/em&gt; will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for an A-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Like an A, but not consistent over time, or weak in a specific area."&lt;/em&gt; will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for a B-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Understand some of the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations but often needs assistance, evidence that the material has had some change on the way of thinking."&lt;/em&gt; will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for a C-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates "Poor" will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for a D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything over 50% is usually at least a D&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes 50% might be better than a D, such as a C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only actual percentage used. All other percentages in this document are only &lt;strong&gt;examples&lt;/strong&gt; and do not apply to this semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the definition of curved, grades are &lt;strong&gt;not curved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people define &lt;em&gt;curved&lt;/em&gt; to mean that grades are adjusted based on some statistics (such as the average) performance of all students in the class. In this sense, grades are not curved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people define &lt;em&gt;curved&lt;/em&gt; to mean that grades are adjusted based on distributions, e.g. a fixed number or percent of students get an A. In this sense, grades are not curved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people define &lt;em&gt;curved&lt;/em&gt; to mean that grades may change depending on what happens during the semester, and in this sense graves are "curved" but this is not the University, Faculty, or Department's definition of curved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University Policy: No fixed grade distribution can be used.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class rank and averages are not taken into account when deciding breakpoints.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No system which produces a fixed number or fixed percentage of A's of A's
is used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No system where the breakpoints are moved based on class averages is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By this system it is entirely possible for every student to get an "A" in the
course if every student demonstrates "A" level mastery of the course material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is also possible for every student to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The percentages required to attain a particular letter grade are not
decided until &lt;em&gt;after the final exam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is to ensure that any surprises or differences between semesters can be taken into account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, if a new assignment or exam proves to be more difficult than previous semesters, the
    percentages required for each letter grade (breakpoints) will lower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a new assignment or exam proves to be less difficult than previous semesters, the percentages
    required for each letter grade will rise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same breakpoints (final percentage required to get an A, B, C, etc.)
apply to everyone.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If one student demonstrates performance as listed above then all students with the same or higher final percentage will receive the same letter grade or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example: if one student demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction."&lt;/em&gt; and has &lt;em&gt;81&lt;/em&gt;% in the course, than any student with &lt;em&gt;81&lt;/em&gt;% or higher will earn at least an "A-". This is just an example, an A is not 81% this semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example: If student X gets an overall 82% and deservers an A, and student Y gets an overall 83%, then student Y will also get an A, regardless of what the instructor thinks of them. This is just an example, an A is not 82% this semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every semester contains different material since every semester we try to improve the course, and we also need to constantly create new questions and assignments to mitigate cheating.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From one semester to the next the breakpoints could be higher or lower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From one exam to the next what percentage demonstrates each of the qualities in the table could be higher or lower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjustments to breakpoints do not depend on class averages.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The class average can be a D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The class average can be an A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructors can not decide to make the breakpoints just whatever they want. Breakpoints are validated by at least one of:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate Chair (Undergraduate Program)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate Chain (Graduate Program)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department Chair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost nothing in the course outline (syllabus) can be changed after the first day of class. Especially not component weights, like the weights of an exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone in the class can get an A at the same time in the same semester.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, for the whole class to get an A, everyone in the class must demonstrate &lt;em&gt;"Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is highly unlikely in large classes, as a basic fact of probability and statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, University Policy ensures it must remain possible, even if it is unlikely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courses/semesters with open-book exams will usually have lower breakpoints than courses/semesters with closed-book exams.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is because open-book exam questions are usually &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; difficult, and avoid asking for very much that can be simply looked up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courses/semesters with open-internet exams will usually have &lt;em&gt;even lower&lt;/em&gt; breakpoints, because the exam questions are usually &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="breakpoint-calculations-and-examples"&gt;Breakpoint Calculations and Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers in this section examples only and will not be used for this course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example hypothetical scenario:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semester 1: The breakpoint for a C- is determined to be 70%. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semester 2: The semester is exactly the same as Semester 1, except that one exam, worth 13% of the overall grade, has more questions that require "original thinking that extends the material" and fewer questions that require "understanding parts of the material"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the exam were judged by itself, the breakpoint for a C- would drop from 80% in semester 1 to 50% in semester 2, a difference of 30%. But the exam is only worth 13% of the overall grade, so the overall breakpoint would probably be about 4% lower in semester 2 than semester 1. (13% x 30% = 3.9%) because in this hypothetical scenario, none of the other exams or assignments changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semester 2: The breakpoint for a C- is determined to be a 66%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breakpoints are not actually decided individually for each assignment, exam, lab, etc. Instead, breakpoints are only decided at the end of the semester of the overall grade. However, the result is the same, since breakpoints can be averaged according to the weights given for each assignment/lab/exam/etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example hypothetical semester:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessment            Weight  Minimum % required for a C-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exam 1                 20%   40%
Exam 2                 20%   50%
Exam 3                 30%   60%
Assignment 1           10%   90%
Assignment 2           10%   80%
Labs                   10%   70%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculation for a C- for the above example:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% * 40% + 20% * 50% + 30% * 60% + 10% * 90% + 10% * 80% + 10% * 70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;= 60% overall required for a C-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same could be done for all the letters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In practice, it is too time-consuming to determine breakpoints for each component,
    so the breakpoints are only decided at the end of the semester, since the calculations are mathematically equivalent anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider an exam, "exam 1" on which every question requires: "Original thinking," or "ability to integrate the material with other subjects," or "ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction." Your score on such an exam should be interpreted as the % of the exam that you got an A on. Or the % of the exam that you did better than an F, D, C or B!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternately, consider an exam, "exam 2" where every question only requires "understanding of parts of the material": your % on that exam is the % of the exam that you didn't get an F on. This should very well be a much higher % than "exam 1."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>How to get Help</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/help.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/help.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Communications Expectations&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#communication-expectations"&gt;Communication Expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#where-to-get-help"&gt;Where to get help?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#discussion-forum"&gt;Discussion Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#office-hours"&gt;Office Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#instructor"&gt;Instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tas"&gt;TAs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#wellness-supports"&gt;Wellness Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#physical-well-being-supports"&gt;Physical Well-being Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#mental-health-supports"&gt;Mental Health Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#immediate-assistance"&gt;Immediate Assistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#safety-and-security-for-students"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="communication-expectations"&gt;Communication Expectations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask questions well before Assignment due dates. Although you have nothing to lose by trying, realize that while the course staff try to provide as much support as possible, they are not obliged to answer last-minute questions (i.e., those within less than 2 business days from the assignment due date). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be polite and courteous. We will not tolerate impolite comments or harassments of any sort on the course forum or to any of the course staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="where-to-get-help"&gt;Where to get help?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions about assignments/projects: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due dates: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything where another student might have the same question: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions about the material covered in lecture/labs: Discussion forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual help with assignments/projects:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get help &lt;strong&gt;during the labs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend the &lt;strong&gt;office hours of a TA.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend the office hours of your instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal questions about you or your mark: Contact the &lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complaints: Contact the &lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReMarking requests: Contact the &lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs will not help you with your marks, even if they're the one who marked it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="discussion-forum"&gt;Discussion Forum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions related to the course and course material, especially if the answer could help another student!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Posting to the forum increases your changes of a &lt;strong&gt;quick response&lt;/strong&gt; since any of the course staff or your classmates are able to answer. 🌠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless your question is personal (E.g., you are feeling unwell and require an EA, you have a question about your mark), all questions should be posted on the Discussion Forum first. Please do not share code from your implementations (configuration settings are OK). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not post your code. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration settings are OK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not post your solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post only questions related to &lt;strong&gt;this course&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be polite, this is not a complaint forum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion forum is on the eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="office-hours"&gt;Office Hours&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your question is related to implementation/configuration issues in the projects/assignments, the TAs are best suited to help you. You can attend TA office hours remotely. &lt;strong&gt;TAs do not provide help outside of Labs and Scheduled Office Hours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your question is related to content covered in class and you need further explanation, please post on the disucssion forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="instructor"&gt;Instructor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;Instructor office hours&lt;/a&gt; is in the course outline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="tas"&gt;TAs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you need help with your projects/assignment code, or help getting something working, the TAs are best suited to help you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend TA office hours remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not eMail TAs&lt;/strong&gt; unless you're having a hard time joining their Zoom/Meet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs do not provide help outside of Labs and Scheduled Office Hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please be polite and courteous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs will not re-grade your work or deal with extensions, excuses, illness, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TA office hours are on the eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wellness-supports"&gt;Wellness Supports&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2024! I hope that you are happily settling into the winter semester at University of Alberta. If you’re still feeling the stress of exams or hoping to develop good health habits going into this new semester, we’re here to help! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that there are many services available, both in person and virtually, for students to help with physical well being? Whether you need a new exercise class, access to more affordable groceries, or mental health supports, read on to discover what is available at U  of A! Taking care of your physical self can help improve your mental well-being and increase your success in your classes as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few key places to connect with resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="physical-well-being-supports"&gt;Physical Well-being Supports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://campusfoodbank.com/"&gt;Campus Food Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://internalcomms.cmail19.com/t/d-l-vuytlz-ihirhlhytl-k/"&gt;WECAN Food Basket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (affordable groceries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/campus-community-recreation/our-programs/rec-guide/index.html"&gt;Campus and Community Recreation Winter 2024 schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CampusCommunityRecreation"&gt;Campus and Community Recreation Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/counselling/workshops.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Weekly%20free%20mindfulness%20and%20yoga%20class%20through%20Counselling%20%20Clinical%20Services"&gt;Weekly free mindfulness and yoga class through Counselling &amp;amp; Clinical Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://guides.library.ualberta.ca/wellbeing"&gt;Use a treadmill desk when studying in the library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="mental-health-supports"&gt;Mental Health Supports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All mental health &amp;amp; wellbeing supports offered to undergraduate students are listed on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/campus-life/health-wellness/index.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Health%20%20Wellness#mental-health-support"&gt;Health + Wellness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page, including options for peer support programs, medical care, and other wellness programs open to you. Counselling &amp;amp; Clinical Services also offers a range of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/counselling/workshops.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=workshops"&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for you to learn how to be a peer support for other students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unsure how to access a resource, please contact the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/dean-of-students/index.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Office%20of%20the%20Dean%20of%20Students"&gt;Office of the Dean of Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for a full listing of services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="immediate-assistance"&gt;Immediate Assistance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is in need of immediate assistance, please reach out to a friend, professor, or staff member. Find a list of immediate support services &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/need-help-now.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=here"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="safety-and-security-for-students"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UA's &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/safety-and-security.html"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protective Services &lt;a href="tel:780-492-5050"&gt;780-492-5050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="contact"></category><category term="wellness"></category></entry><entry><title>Labs</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/labs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/labs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lab Procedure, Lab Assignments, Lab Marking&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#lab-things-go-here"&gt;Lab Things Go Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lab-things-go-here"&gt;Lab Things Go Here&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lab material is on &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1bFzss045P-FRPCSXZpzdlLyLCHm29f4y?usp=drive_link"&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; or eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must be logged into your UA account to access the Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the process of moving things to Google Drive, so if its not on eClass check there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning Resources &amp; Reference Materials</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/resources.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/resources.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Resources, Reference Materials, Notes, Videos, Slides&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#software"&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#video-tutorials"&gt;Video Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#reference-materials"&gt;Reference Materials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="software"&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/Projects/automated-combinatorial-testing-for-software/downloadable-tools"&gt;ACTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/resources/ACTS3.2.zip"&gt;ACTS 3.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="video-tutorials"&gt;Video Tutorials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VN9-uTRFZ94"&gt;RESTful Web Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is REST?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a RESTful web service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do REST requests and responses look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I70JekEgrKI"&gt;Introduction to Gradle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a build system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is gradle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use gradle to build Tartan Platform project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aN7xKzAwIkw"&gt;Object-relational mapping (ORM) and Hibernate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Object-relational mapping (or, ORM)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Hibernate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M16oeCOLpvg"&gt;Introduction to Dropwizard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Dropwizard?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Dropwizard help create and manage web services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="reference-materials"&gt;Reference Materials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/archive/msdn-magazine/2006/november/uncover-security-design-flaws-using-the-stride-approach"&gt;STRIDE Threat Modeling Process by Hernan et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/resources/STRIDE.pdf"&gt;PDF Copy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/resources/KanerSoftwareMetrics.pdf"&gt;Software Engineering Metrics: What Do They Measure and How Do We Know?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/resources/PaperList.pdf"&gt;List of Related Research Papers for those interested to learn about SW Quality Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="references"></category><category term="videos"></category></entry><entry><title>Project</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tartan Smart Home System&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3 id="tartan-smart-home-system"&gt;Tartan Smart Home System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PbZUAZezH3af_Fu7KQ3N2T6JpkIX15Yq/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;System Description PDF&lt;/a&gt; on GDrive you must be logged into your UA account&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt; links are out of date!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/tartan/build.html"&gt;Tartan Build Instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="group-assignments"&gt;Group Assignments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/basics.html"&gt;Group Assignment 1: Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/testing.html"&gt;Group Assignment 2: Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/testing-in-production.html"&gt;Group Assignment 3: Testing in Production&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/static-analysis.html"&gt;Group Assignment 4: Static Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput402.github.io/group/technical-debt.html"&gt;Group Assignment 5: Technical Debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Project: Tartan Smart Home System</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/tartan/build.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/tartan/build.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tartan System&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id="platform-installation-and-configuration"&gt;Platform Installation and Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial configuration for the Tartan Smart Home System is done via a YAML
file named &lt;em&gt;config.yml&lt;/em&gt;. The configuration file contains the initial settings
needed for the system including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The configuration information for the Hubs connected to the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The timer for the data historian (see below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The configuration settings for database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has prepared docker containers to quickly get the system up and
running, but for understanding how the system actually works, we describe the
technical components and their configuration below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="dependencies"&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform is written in Java, using Java 11. If OpenJDK is used,
dependencies for javafx may need to be installed additionally (e.g., &lt;code&gt;apt-get
install openjfx&lt;/code&gt; on Ubuntu). Gradle 7.3 is used as a build system and already
included with the gradlew wrapper. Various Java dependencies are automatically
downloaded during the build from the public Maven repository. MySQL 8.0 is used
as database engine. Python 3.7 is used to execute the house simulator/hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="installationdownload-links"&gt;Installation/Download links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gradle: https://gradle.org/install/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Gradle Wrapper: go to the directory and run &lt;code&gt;gradle wrapper&lt;/code&gt;, then you can start using &lt;code&gt;gradlew&lt;/code&gt;
      e.g., 
      &lt;code&gt;cd smart-home/Platform
      gradle wrapper&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java (Windows): https://www.oracle.com/ca-en/java/technologies/javase/jdk11-archive-downloads.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MySQL (Ubuntu): https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-mysql-on-ubuntu-18-04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MySQL (Windows): https://downloads.mysql.com/archives/installer/ Change version to 8.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker (Ubuntu): https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/ubuntu/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Desktop (Docker for Windows): https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-windows/install/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows Subsytem for Linux (needed for Docker Desktop): https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10#step-4---download-the-linux-kernel-update-package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="database-configuration"&gt;Database Configuration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying database used in the current system is &lt;a href="https://www.mysql.com/"&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;config.yml&lt;/em&gt;
file contains the basic settings for this database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;database&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# the name of the JDBC driver to use&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;driverClass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;com.mysql.cj.jdbc.Driver&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# the DB username&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;tartan&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# the DB password&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;password&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;tartan1234&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# the JDBC URL; the database is called TartanHome&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;jdbc:mysql://localhost/TartanHome?useJDBCCompliantTimezoneShift=true&amp;amp;useLegacyDatetimeCode=false&amp;amp;serverTimezone=UTC&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;# Allow Hibernate to create tables&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p p-Indicator"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;hibernate.dialect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;org.hibernate.dialect.MySQLDialect&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# leave it to hibernate to update/create the database.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Warning, this is generally considered a bad setting for production&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;hibernate.hbm2ddl.auto&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;update&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, the system expects access to a MySQL database on localhost with a user
named &lt;strong&gt;tartan&lt;/strong&gt; with a password of &lt;strong&gt;tartan1234&lt;/strong&gt; and a database named
&lt;strong&gt;TartanHome&lt;/strong&gt;. You can use the sample SQL script &lt;em&gt;init.sql&lt;/em&gt; found inside the
Database subfolder to create the database and the user. Tables within this
database are automatically created when the system is run. Note that these
credentials are specified in the system YAML configuration file (&lt;em&gt;config.yml&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="building-the-platform"&gt;Building the Platform&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is currently developed in &lt;code&gt;smart-home&lt;/code&gt; folder. It contains the
Tartan Service Platform code as well as the house simulator (the Hub).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current implementation uses Gradle as the build system. You may want to use the
gradle wrapper &lt;strong&gt;gradlew&lt;/strong&gt; available in the relevant folders which will automatically
download and use the correct gradle version. To that end, use &lt;code&gt;./gradlew&lt;/code&gt; in Ubuntu
and macOS, or &lt;code&gt;gradlew.bat&lt;/code&gt; in Windows. You can supply the same parameters to &lt;strong&gt;gradlew&lt;/strong&gt;
as simple &lt;strong&gt;gradle&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g., &lt;code&gt;./gradlew build&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Platform project (&lt;em&gt;smart-home&lt;/em&gt; directory), executing &lt;code&gt;./gradlew shadowJar&lt;/code&gt;
inside the &lt;em&gt;/Platform&lt;/em&gt; subfolder will create a single &lt;em&gt;tartan-1.0-SNAPSHOT.jar&lt;/em&gt;
file that contains the Platform and all dependencies. This file will be created
inside the &lt;em&gt;/Platform/build/libs&lt;/em&gt; subfolder. The Platform can then be launched
with &lt;code&gt;java -jar build/libs/tartan-1.0-SNAPSHOT.jar &amp;lt;parameters&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; (see below for more
details about the parameters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these decisions were made for legacy reasons. Your team may change all
of these technical decisions and tooling if preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="running-the-system"&gt;Running the System&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system consists of the following components that must be launched:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or more House Hubs (the house simulator, inside &lt;em&gt;smart-home/HouseSimulator&lt;/em&gt; subfolder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The MySQL database (&lt;em&gt;smart-home/Database&lt;/em&gt; subfolder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tartan Service Platform (&lt;em&gt;smart-home/Platform&lt;/em&gt; subfolder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A docker setup is provided with a finished configuration in the smart-home
folder that starts two houses. You can launch it with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;up&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to run this version, note that there is a separate config file,
&lt;em&gt;config.docker.yml&lt;/em&gt;, that is used in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have made changes and want your docker setup to reflect it, run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;docker-compose&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;down&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;docker-compose&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;build&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--no-cache&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;docker-compose&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;up
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id="windows-differences"&gt;Windows differences&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and under "Container / Apps" remember to "Start" the "smart-home" container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the instructions to launch the components individually without docker.
However, it is recommended to use Docker Compose instead of manually controlling
the start and shutdown of the components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="the-house-simulator"&gt;The House Simulator&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house simulator is a simple Python program that takes two command line
arguments: the host and port to listen for incoming connections. To run the
house simulator simply execute the following command inside &lt;em&gt;/HouseSimulator&lt;/em&gt;
directory (port will need to be changed for each house if simulating multiple
houses):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;python3&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;simple_server.py&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;localhost&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;5050&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start a second house, consistent with the default &lt;em&gt;config.yml&lt;/em&gt; configuration,
execute the following command on another command window:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;python3&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;simple_server.py&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;localhost&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;5051&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id="the-historian-database"&gt;The Historian Database&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must start the MySQL server to log house history. You have to make sure that
you start the database before you start the platform. MySQL is typically
started via the following command in Ubuntu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;systemctl&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;start&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;mysql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start the MySQL service in Windows:
Search for "services" in the Windows search bar, then scroll down and start the "MySQL" service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If running manually (not using &lt;code&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt;) then you need to create the database and user manually as well. The following example is for a Windows system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd C:\Users\UserName\Documents\CMPUT 402\Tartan\smart-home\Database
&amp;quot;C:\ProgramFiles\MySQL\MySQL Server 8.0\bin\mysql.exe&amp;quot; -u root -p 
source init.sql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id="the-tartan-smart-home-service"&gt;The Tartan Smart Home Service&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, again, requires MySQL server. The Platform can be run using the following
command (from &lt;em&gt;/Platform&lt;/em&gt; subfolder):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;java&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-jar&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;build/libs/tartan-1.0-SNAPSHOT.jar&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;server&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;config.yml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be executed with &lt;code&gt;./gradlew run&lt;/code&gt;, which will pass the same
parameters automatically. Note that the platform must be launched after the
database and the house hub/simulator scripts are running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the standard way to run a &lt;a href="https://www.dropwizard.io/en/stable/getting-started.html"&gt;Dropwizard
application&lt;/a&gt;. The
&lt;code&gt;server&lt;/code&gt; command runs your application as an HTTP server and the YAML file
&lt;em&gt;config.yml&lt;/em&gt; contains the initial configuration settings. If the system is
running correctly, then you should be able to access it by navigating to the
following URL in a web browser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8080/smarthome/state/&amp;lt;housename&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;strong&gt;mse&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;cmu&lt;/strong&gt; are the names of the default houses configured in
config.yml. The default username and password for access to the system is also
configured in this file ("admin" and "1234" for &lt;strong&gt;mse&lt;/strong&gt;, "admin" and "5678" for
&lt;strong&gt;cmu&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id="possible-issues"&gt;Possible issues&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to run The Platform, you may encounter the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;javax.net.ssl.SSLHandshakeException: No appropriate protocol (protocol is disabled or cipher suites are inappropriate)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appending &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;enabledTLSProtocols=TLSv1.2&lt;/code&gt; to the end of the &lt;code&gt;${database.url}&lt;/code&gt; property in &lt;em&gt;config.yml&lt;/em&gt; will fix the issue (see the &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/67918194/9985287"&gt;StackOverflow solution&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARM based Mac Issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARM based macs (M1 or M2) might have issues running MySQL. If that happens, make sure you are running MySQL 8.0 and not any lower version, even when running with Docker.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="tartan"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Schedule</title><link href="https://cmput402.github.io/general/schedule.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput402.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/schedule.html</id><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course schedule is updated in this &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1nI9E-naS2anf7boJF33eY43MlRjv1f0ymMJ3LdIinss/edit"&gt;Google Sheet&lt;/a&gt;.
You need to be logged in as your University of Alberta CCID/eMail account to view it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="schedule"></category><category term="homework"></category></entry></feed>