<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>CMPUT 301 - general</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/feeds/general.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cmput301.github.io/</id><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><subtitle>Software Engineering</subtitle><entry><title>Course Outline Fall 2024</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-09-01:/general/outline.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;University of Alberta &lt;br&gt; CMPUT 301 - Software Engineering &lt;br&gt; LEC- &lt;br&gt; Fall 2024&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;University of Alberta &lt;br&gt; CMPUT 301 - Software Engineering &lt;br&gt; LEC- &lt;br&gt; Fall 2024&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="coming-soon"&gt;Coming soon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eClass Page&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home Page&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/"&gt;https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#coming-soon"&gt;Coming soon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="outline"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category><category term="contact"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Assignment 5: Presentation Marking Rubric</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/presentation-rubric.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-04-05:/general/presentation-rubric.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#marking"&gt;Marking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#evaluating-deliverables-based-on-presentation-content"&gt;Evaluating Deliverables Based on Presentation Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the presentation marking rubric is to outline precise evaluation criteria for the assessment of the group assignment 5 presentation. Its aim is to provide clear guidance to presenters, ensuring they have a thorough understanding of what is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#marking"&gt;Marking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#evaluating-deliverables-based-on-presentation-content"&gt;Evaluating Deliverables Based on Presentation Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the presentation marking rubric is to outline precise evaluation criteria for the assessment of the group assignment 5 presentation. Its aim is to provide clear guidance to presenters, ensuring they have a thorough understanding of what is expected of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slides&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to use readable fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use short phrases instead of paragraphs of text. Avoid crowded text-only slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use pictures, diagrams etc., whenever possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add slide numbers so that it is easy to ask questions about specific slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivering the talk&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be positive and (pretend to be?) interested and excited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak loudly and clearly &amp;amp; avoid being monotonous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Face the audience and look at them and try to engage the audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your talk entertaining (without overdoing it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehearse your presentation well enough that you don’t need to keep reading off your slides. If you are always reading off the slides, then  the audience could simply read your slides and not listen to you at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anticipate things you need to highlight and use boxes etc to highlight them on the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present the project to the class&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your presentation must be targeted to the audience who are in the class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentations will be done by group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation should be about 8 minutes, no more. Try NOT to wrap up the presentation really early. You MUST finish your presentation within the time constraints so please rehearse properly. You will lose 2 marks if you run over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation should cover all the aspects of group assignment 5 including the five points which should be in the report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use PowerPoint or Google Slides or whatever presentation software you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will need to present in lab in person during lab time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All group members will have to present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be able to answer questions about the presentation and your work so far&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are expected to attend each other's presentations and ask questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id="marking"&gt;Marking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation quality is marked by the below rubric (out of 20):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Component&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Excellent (5)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Good (4)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Satisfactory (3)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unsatisfactory (2)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Poor (1)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are clear, readable, and well-designed. Text is large enough to be seen from the back of the room. Figures are appropriately sized and labeled. No more than five bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are mostly clear, readable, and well-designed. Text is large enough to be seen from most of the room. Figures are adequately sized and labeled. No more than seven bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are somewhat clear, readable, and well-designed. Text is large enough to be seen from the front of the room. Figures are somewhat sized and labeled. No more than nine bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are unclear, unreadable, or poorly designed. Text is too small to be seen from the back of the room. Figures are too large or too small and unlabeled. More than nine bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are missing, illegible, or incomprehensible. Text is too small to be seen from anywhere in the room. Figures are irrelevant or absent. Too many bullet points per slide or no bullet points at all.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has a clear introduction, body, and conclusion. Transitions between slides are smooth and logical. Main points are highlighted and supported by evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has an introduction, body, and conclusion. Transitions between slides are mostly smooth and logical. Main points are stated and supported by some evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has an introduction, body, and conclusion. Transitions between slides are somewhat smooth and logical. Main points are mentioned and supported by weak evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation lacks a clear introduction, body, or conclusion. Transitions between slides are abrupt or illogical. Main points are unclear or unsupported by evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has no discernible structure or flow. Transitions between slides are nonexistent or confusing. Main points are missing or irrelevant.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Demonstration of quality evaluation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate a comprehensive understanding of quality evaluation principles using SonarQube. Presenters provide a comprehensive and detailed overview of the current CI pipeline. Presenters offer insightful and well-reasoned advice on addressing current technical debt, providing clear justification and actionable recommendations. Presenters engage in a thorough and insightful discussion of metrics and tool changes, offering clear rationale and considerations for potential modifications.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate a solid understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, with clear explanations and examples. Presenters provide a clear and informative discussion of the current CI pipeline, covering key aspects with sufficient detail. Presenters provide solid advice on addressing current debt, supported by logical reasoning and relevant examples. Presenters provide a coherent and informative discussion of metrics and tool changes, supported by logical reasoning and relevant examples.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate a basic understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, but with some gaps in clarity or depth. Presenters provide an adequate overview of the current CI pipeline, though some areas may lack depth or clarity. Presenters provide basic advice on addressing current debt, though some aspects may lack depth or specificity. Presenters provide a basic overview of metrics and potential tool changes, though depth and justification may vary.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate poor understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, with significant gaps or inaccuracies. Presenters provide a poor or incomplete description of the current CI pipeline, with significant gaps or omissions. Presenters provide limited or unclear advice on addressing current debt, with weak reasoning or insufficient detail. Presenters offer limited or unclear insights into metrics and tool changes, with weak justification or relevance.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate little to no understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, with major inaccuracies or misconceptions. Presenters fail to effectively discuss the current CI pipeline, lacking coherence or relevant details. Presenters fail to provide meaningful advice on addressing current debt, lacking coherence or relevance. Presenters fail to effectively discuss metrics and tool changes, lacking coherence or substantive content.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ability to answer questions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer all questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are respectful and courteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer most questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide some additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are respectful and courteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer some questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide little additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are respectful and courteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer few questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide no additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are disrespectful or discourteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer no questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide irrelevant or inaccurate information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are rude or hostile to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id="evaluating-deliverables-based-on-presentation-content"&gt;Evaluating Deliverables Based on Presentation Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/group/technical-debt.html"&gt;Group Assignment 5: Technical Debt&lt;/a&gt;, we will use both the content of your report and presentation to grade the 5 points from the deliverables. The weight of the content of the presentation for the main grading is given below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality evaluation using SonarQube (points 1 and 2):  7.5 out of 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussing current CI pipeline (point 3): 2.5 out of 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on paying back current debt (point 4): 3.75 out of 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion of metrics &amp;amp; tool changes (point 5): 2.5 out of 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total presentation content grade: 16.25 out of 70&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note that this section is separate from the presentation marks, which will be graded out of 20 according to the rubric in the &lt;a href="#marking"&gt;table above&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Individual</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/individual.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-03-20:/general/individual.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Individual Assignments&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3 id="assignments"&gt;Assignments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/individual/testing-theory.html"&gt;Individual Assignment 1: Testing Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/individual/testing-mocks.html"&gt;Individual Assignment 2: Testing with Mocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/individual/performance-assessment.html"&gt;Individual Assignment 3: Performance Assessment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graduate students 501 only&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/individual/research-presentation.html"&gt;Research Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="assignment"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Grade Letters</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/grade_letters.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/grade_letters.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Grading System, Percentages and Letters, Breakpoint Calculation&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#grading-system-percentages-and-letters"&gt;Grading System: Percentages and Letters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#breakpoint-calculations-and-examples"&gt;Breakpoint Calculations and Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="grading-system-percentages-and-letters"&gt;Grading System: Percentages and Letters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not use pre-defined percentages of your final mark to compute your final grade, but instead use our judgement of how your final percentage indicates the level of mastery in the table below for an A, B, C, D+. This is done after the final exam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the standard system in use by most Computing Science courses at the University of Alberta. However, it may not be what you are used to from other institutions.
The department of Computing Science believes this produces a fair evaluation and our extensive experience supports this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: center;"&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: center;"&gt;Descriptor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align: left;"&gt;Interpretation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;A+&lt;br&gt;A&lt;br&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Excellent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;B+&lt;br&gt;B&lt;br&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Good&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Like an A, but not consistent over time, or weak in a specific area.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;C+&lt;br&gt;C&lt;br&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Satisfactory&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Understand the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations on own and to more complex situations with hints, evidence that the material has changed the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Poor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Understand some of the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations but often needs assistance, evidence that the material has had some change on the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Minimal&lt;br&gt;Pass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Shows some understanding of parts of the material, cannot apply it without some direction, little evidence that the material has changed the way of thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;Failure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: left;"&gt;Little evidence of understanding of even the surface issues, poor analysis and synthesis, inability to apply the material.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find a copy of this table on the &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/computing-science/resources/policy-information/department-course-policies.html"&gt;Department Course Policies&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The table listed above is used to translate the final percentage in the course to a letter grade by using grade breakpoints after the final exam.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is done by using &lt;em&gt;breakpoints&lt;/em&gt;: each letter grade is given a minimum percentage required to get that letter grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction."&lt;/em&gt; will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for an A-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Like an A, but not consistent over time, or weak in a specific area."&lt;/em&gt; will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for a B-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Understand some of the core material but not its subtleties, can apply it to simple situations but often needs assistance, evidence that the material has had some change on the way of thinking."&lt;/em&gt; will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for a C-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum overall percentage demonstrates "Poor" will be the minimum percentage "breakpoint" for a D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything over 50% is usually at least a D&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes 50% might be better than a D, such as a C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only actual percentage used. All other percentages in this document are only &lt;strong&gt;examples&lt;/strong&gt; and do not apply to this semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the definition of curved, grades are &lt;strong&gt;not curved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people define &lt;em&gt;curved&lt;/em&gt; to mean that grades are adjusted based on some statistics (such as the average) performance of all students in the class. In this sense, grades are not curved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people define &lt;em&gt;curved&lt;/em&gt; to mean that grades are adjusted based on distributions, e.g. a fixed number or percent of students get an A. In this sense, grades are not curved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people define &lt;em&gt;curved&lt;/em&gt; to mean that grades may change depending on what happens during the semester, and in this sense graves are "curved" but this is not the University, Faculty, or Department's definition of curved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University Policy: No fixed grade distribution can be used.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class rank and averages are not taken into account when deciding breakpoints.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No system which produces a fixed number or fixed percentage of A's of A's
is used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No system where the breakpoints are moved based on class averages is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By this system it is entirely possible for every student to get an "A" in the
course if every student demonstrates "A" level mastery of the course material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is also possible for every student to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The percentages required to attain a particular letter grade are not
decided until &lt;em&gt;after the final exam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is to ensure that any surprises or differences between semesters can be taken into account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, if a new assignment or exam proves to be more difficult than previous semesters, the
    percentages required for each letter grade (breakpoints) will lower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a new assignment or exam proves to be less difficult than previous semesters, the percentages
    required for each letter grade will rise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same breakpoints (final percentage required to get an A, B, C, etc.)
apply to everyone.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If one student demonstrates performance as listed above then all students with the same or higher final percentage will receive the same letter grade or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example: if one student demonstrates &lt;em&gt;"Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction."&lt;/em&gt; and has &lt;em&gt;81&lt;/em&gt;% in the course, than any student with &lt;em&gt;81&lt;/em&gt;% or higher will earn at least an "A-". This is just an example, an A is not 81% this semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example: If student X gets an overall 82% and deservers an A, and student Y gets an overall 83%, then student Y will also get an A, regardless of what the instructor thinks of them. This is just an example, an A is not 82% this semester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every semester contains different material since every semester we try to improve the course, and we also need to constantly create new questions and assignments to mitigate cheating.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From one semester to the next the breakpoints could be higher or lower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From one exam to the next what percentage demonstrates each of the qualities in the table could be higher or lower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjustments to breakpoints do not depend on class averages.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The class average can be a D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The class average can be an A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructors can not decide to make the breakpoints just whatever they want. Breakpoints are validated by at least one of:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate Chair (Undergraduate Program)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate Chain (Graduate Program)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department Chair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost nothing in the course outline (syllabus) can be changed after the first day of class. Especially not component weights, like the weights of an exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone in the class can get an A at the same time in the same semester.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, for the whole class to get an A, everyone in the class must demonstrate &lt;em&gt;"Consistently original thinking that extends the material, demonstrated depth and breadth in the material, ability to integrate material with other subjects, ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is highly unlikely in large classes, as a basic fact of probability and statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, University Policy ensures it must remain possible, even if it is unlikely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courses/semesters with open-book exams will usually have lower breakpoints than courses/semesters with closed-book exams.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is because open-book exam questions are usually &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; difficult, and avoid asking for very much that can be simply looked up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courses/semesters with open-internet exams will usually have &lt;em&gt;even lower&lt;/em&gt; breakpoints, because the exam questions are usually &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="breakpoint-calculations-and-examples"&gt;Breakpoint Calculations and Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers in this section examples only and will not be used for this course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example hypothetical scenario:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semester 1: The breakpoint for a C- is determined to be 70%. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semester 2: The semester is exactly the same as Semester 1, except that one exam, worth 13% of the overall grade, has more questions that require "original thinking that extends the material" and fewer questions that require "understanding parts of the material"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the exam were judged by itself, the breakpoint for a C- would drop from 80% in semester 1 to 50% in semester 2, a difference of 30%. But the exam is only worth 13% of the overall grade, so the overall breakpoint would probably be about 4% lower in semester 2 than semester 1. (13% x 30% = 3.9%) because in this hypothetical scenario, none of the other exams or assignments changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semester 2: The breakpoint for a C- is determined to be a 66%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breakpoints are not actually decided individually for each assignment, exam, lab, etc. Instead, breakpoints are only decided at the end of the semester of the overall grade. However, the result is the same, since breakpoints can be averaged according to the weights given for each assignment/lab/exam/etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example hypothetical semester:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessment            Weight  Minimum % required for a C-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exam 1                 20%   40%
Exam 2                 20%   50%
Exam 3                 30%   60%
Assignment 1           10%   90%
Assignment 2           10%   80%
Labs                   10%   70%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculation for a C- for the above example:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% * 40% + 20% * 50% + 30% * 60% + 10% * 90% + 10% * 80% + 10% * 70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;= 60% overall required for a C-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same could be done for all the letters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In practice, it is too time-consuming to determine breakpoints for each component,
    so the breakpoints are only decided at the end of the semester, since the calculations are mathematically equivalent anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider an exam, "exam 1" on which every question requires: "Original thinking," or "ability to integrate the material with other subjects," or "ability to analyze and synthesize material at various levels of abstraction." Your score on such an exam should be interpreted as the % of the exam that you got an A on. Or the % of the exam that you did better than an F, D, C or B!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternately, consider an exam, "exam 2" where every question only requires "understanding of parts of the material": your % on that exam is the % of the exam that you didn't get an F on. This should very well be a much higher % than "exam 1."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Project</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tartan Smart Home System&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3 id="tartan-smart-home-system"&gt;Tartan Smart Home System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PbZUAZezH3af_Fu7KQ3N2T6JpkIX15Yq/view?usp=drive_link"&gt;System Description PDF&lt;/a&gt; on GDrive you must be logged into your UA account&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt; links are out of date!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/tartan/build.html"&gt;Tartan Build Instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="group-assignments"&gt;Group Assignments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/group/basics.html"&gt;Group Assignment 1: Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/group/testing.html"&gt;Group Assignment 2: Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/group/testing-in-production.html"&gt;Group Assignment 3: Testing in Production&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/group/static-analysis.html"&gt;Group Assignment 4: Static Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/group/technical-debt.html"&gt;Group Assignment 5: Technical Debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="marking-rubric"&gt;Marking Rubric&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/presentation-rubric.html"&gt;Group Assignment 5: Presentation Marking Rubric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>How to get Help</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/help.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/help.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Communications Expectations&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#communication-expectations"&gt;Communication Expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#where-to-get-help"&gt;Where to get help?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#discussion-forum"&gt;Discussion Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#office-hours"&gt;Office Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#instructor"&gt;Instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tas"&gt;TAs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#wellness-supports"&gt;Wellness Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#physical-well-being-supports"&gt;Physical Well-being Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#mental-health-supports"&gt;Mental Health Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#immediate-assistance"&gt;Immediate Assistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#safety-and-security-for-students"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="communication-expectations"&gt;Communication Expectations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask questions well before Assignment due dates. Although you have nothing to lose by trying, realize that while the course staff try to provide as much support as possible, they are not obliged to answer last-minute questions (i.e., those within less than 2 business days from the assignment due date). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be polite and courteous. We will not tolerate impolite comments or harassments of any sort on the course forum or to any of the course staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="where-to-get-help"&gt;Where to get help?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions about assignments/projects: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due dates: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything where another student might have the same question: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions about the material covered in lecture/labs: Discussion forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual help with assignments/projects:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get help &lt;strong&gt;during the labs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend the &lt;strong&gt;office hours of a TA.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend the office hours of your instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal questions about you or your mark: Contact the &lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complaints: Contact the &lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReMarking requests: Contact the &lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs will not help you with your marks, even if they're the one who marked it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="discussion-forum"&gt;Discussion Forum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions related to the course and course material, especially if the answer could help another student!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Posting to the forum increases your changes of a &lt;strong&gt;quick response&lt;/strong&gt; since any of the course staff or your classmates are able to answer. 🌠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless your question is personal (E.g., you are feeling unwell and require an EA, you have a question about your mark), all questions should be posted on the Discussion Forum first. Please do not share code from your implementations (configuration settings are OK). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not post your code. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration settings are OK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not post your solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post only questions related to &lt;strong&gt;this course&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be polite, this is not a complaint forum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion forum is on the eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="office-hours"&gt;Office Hours&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your question is related to implementation/configuration issues in the projects/assignments, the TAs are best suited to help you. You can attend TA office hours remotely. &lt;strong&gt;TAs do not provide help outside of Labs and Scheduled Office Hours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your question is related to content covered in class and you need further explanation, please post on the disucssion forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="instructor"&gt;Instructor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;Instructor office hours&lt;/a&gt; is in the course outline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="tas"&gt;TAs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you need help with your projects/assignment code, or help getting something working, the TAs are best suited to help you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend TA office hours remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not eMail TAs&lt;/strong&gt; unless you're having a hard time joining their Zoom/Meet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs do not provide help outside of Labs and Scheduled Office Hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please be polite and courteous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs will not re-grade your work or deal with extensions, excuses, illness, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TA office hours are on the eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wellness-supports"&gt;Wellness Supports&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2024! I hope that you are happily settling into the winter semester at University of Alberta. If you’re still feeling the stress of exams or hoping to develop good health habits going into this new semester, we’re here to help! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that there are many services available, both in person and virtually, for students to help with physical well being? Whether you need a new exercise class, access to more affordable groceries, or mental health supports, read on to discover what is available at U  of A! Taking care of your physical self can help improve your mental well-being and increase your success in your classes as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few key places to connect with resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="physical-well-being-supports"&gt;Physical Well-being Supports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://campusfoodbank.com/"&gt;Campus Food Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://internalcomms.cmail19.com/t/d-l-vuytlz-ihirhlhytl-k/"&gt;WECAN Food Basket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (affordable groceries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/campus-community-recreation/our-programs/rec-guide/index.html"&gt;Campus and Community Recreation Winter 2024 schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CampusCommunityRecreation"&gt;Campus and Community Recreation Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/counselling/workshops.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Weekly%20free%20mindfulness%20and%20yoga%20class%20through%20Counselling%20%20Clinical%20Services"&gt;Weekly free mindfulness and yoga class through Counselling &amp;amp; Clinical Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://guides.library.ualberta.ca/wellbeing"&gt;Use a treadmill desk when studying in the library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="mental-health-supports"&gt;Mental Health Supports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All mental health &amp;amp; wellbeing supports offered to undergraduate students are listed on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/campus-life/health-wellness/index.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Health%20%20Wellness#mental-health-support"&gt;Health + Wellness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page, including options for peer support programs, medical care, and other wellness programs open to you. Counselling &amp;amp; Clinical Services also offers a range of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/counselling/workshops.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=workshops"&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for you to learn how to be a peer support for other students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unsure how to access a resource, please contact the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/dean-of-students/index.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Office%20of%20the%20Dean%20of%20Students"&gt;Office of the Dean of Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for a full listing of services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="immediate-assistance"&gt;Immediate Assistance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is in need of immediate assistance, please reach out to a friend, professor, or staff member. Find a list of immediate support services &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/need-help-now.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=here"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="safety-and-security-for-students"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UA's &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/safety-and-security.html"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protective Services &lt;a href="tel:780-492-5050"&gt;780-492-5050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="contact"></category><category term="wellness"></category></entry><entry><title>Labs</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/labs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/labs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lab Procedure, Lab Assignments, Lab Marking&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#lab-things-go-here"&gt;Lab Things Go Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lab-things-go-here"&gt;Lab Things Go Here&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lab material is on &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1bFzss045P-FRPCSXZpzdlLyLCHm29f4y?usp=drive_link"&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; or eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must be logged into your UA account to access the Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the process of moving things to Google Drive, so if its not on eClass check there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning Resources &amp; Reference Materials</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/resources.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/resources.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Resources, Reference Materials, Notes, Videos, Slides&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#software"&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#video-tutorials"&gt;Video Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#reference-materials"&gt;Reference Materials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="software"&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/Projects/automated-combinatorial-testing-for-software/downloadable-tools"&gt;ACTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/resources/ACTS3.2.zip"&gt;ACTS 3.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="video-tutorials"&gt;Video Tutorials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VN9-uTRFZ94"&gt;RESTful Web Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is REST?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a RESTful web service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do REST requests and responses look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I70JekEgrKI"&gt;Introduction to Gradle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a build system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is gradle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use gradle to build Tartan Platform project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aN7xKzAwIkw"&gt;Object-relational mapping (ORM) and Hibernate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Object-relational mapping (or, ORM)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Hibernate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M16oeCOLpvg"&gt;Introduction to Dropwizard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Dropwizard?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Dropwizard help create and manage web services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="reference-materials"&gt;Reference Materials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/archive/msdn-magazine/2006/november/uncover-security-design-flaws-using-the-stride-approach"&gt;STRIDE Threat Modeling Process by Hernan et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/resources/STRIDE.pdf"&gt;PDF Copy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/resources/KanerSoftwareMetrics.pdf"&gt;Software Engineering Metrics: What Do They Measure and How Do We Know?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/resources/PaperList.pdf"&gt;List of Related Research Papers for those interested to learn about SW Quality Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.martinfowler.com/articles/mocksArentStubs.html"&gt;Mocks aren't Stubs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/workflowsOfRefactoring/"&gt;Martin Fowler's Refactoring Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="references"></category><category term="videos"></category></entry><entry><title>Schedule</title><link href="https://cmput301.github.io/general/schedule.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/schedule.html</id><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course schedule is updated in this &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1nI9E-naS2anf7boJF33eY43MlRjv1f0ymMJ3LdIinss/edit"&gt;Google Sheet&lt;/a&gt;.
You need to be logged in as your University of Alberta CCID/eMail account to view it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="schedule"></category><category term="homework"></category></entry></feed>