<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>CMPUT 301 - general</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/feeds/general.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/</id><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><subtitle>Software Engineering</subtitle><entry><title>Course Outline Fall 2024</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-09-01:/general/outline.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;University of Alberta &lt;br&gt; CMPUT 301 - Software Engineering &lt;br&gt; LEC- &lt;br&gt; Fall 2024&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;University of Alberta &lt;br&gt; CMPUT 301 - Software Engineering &lt;br&gt; LEC- &lt;br&gt; Fall 2024&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="coming-soon"&gt;Coming soon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eClass Page&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home Page&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/"&gt;https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#coming-soon"&gt;Coming soon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="outline"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category><category term="contact"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Assignment 5: Presentation Marking Rubric</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/presentation-rubric.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-04-05:/general/presentation-rubric.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#this-is-currently-a-copy-of-the-402-presentation-requirements-and-needs-to-be-updated-for-301"&gt;This is currently a copy of the 402 presentation requirements and needs to be updated for 301&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#marking"&gt;Marking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#evaluating-deliverables-based-on-presentation-content"&gt;Evaluating Deliverables Based on Presentation Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="this-is-currently-a-copy-of-the-402-presentation-requirements-and-needs-to-be-updated-for-301"&gt;This is currently a copy of the 402 presentation requirements and needs to be updated for 301&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the presentation marking …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#this-is-currently-a-copy-of-the-402-presentation-requirements-and-needs-to-be-updated-for-301"&gt;This is currently a copy of the 402 presentation requirements and needs to be updated for 301&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#marking"&gt;Marking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#evaluating-deliverables-based-on-presentation-content"&gt;Evaluating Deliverables Based on Presentation Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="this-is-currently-a-copy-of-the-402-presentation-requirements-and-needs-to-be-updated-for-301"&gt;This is currently a copy of the 402 presentation requirements and needs to be updated for 301&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the presentation marking rubric is to outline precise evaluation criteria for the assessment of the group assignment 5 presentation. Its aim is to provide clear guidance to presenters, ensuring they have a thorough understanding of what is expected of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slides&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to use readable fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use short phrases instead of paragraphs of text. Avoid crowded text-only slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use pictures, diagrams etc., whenever possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add slide numbers so that it is easy to ask questions about specific slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivering the talk&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be positive and (pretend to be?) interested and excited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak loudly and clearly &amp;amp; avoid being monotonous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Face the audience and look at them and try to engage the audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your talk entertaining (without overdoing it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehearse your presentation well enough that you don’t need to keep reading off your slides. If you are always reading off the slides, then  the audience could simply read your slides and not listen to you at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anticipate things you need to highlight and use boxes etc to highlight them on the slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present the project to the class&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your presentation must be targeted to the audience who are in the class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentations will be done by group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation should be about 8 minutes, no more. Try NOT to wrap up the presentation really early. You MUST finish your presentation within the time constraints so please rehearse properly. You will lose 2 marks if you run over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation should cover all the aspects of group assignment 5 including the five points which should be in the report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use PowerPoint or Google Slides or whatever presentation software you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will need to present in lab in person during lab time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All group members will have to present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be able to answer questions about the presentation and your work so far&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are expected to attend each other's presentations and ask questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id="marking"&gt;Marking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation quality is marked by the below rubric (out of 20):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Component&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Excellent (5)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Good (4)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Satisfactory (3)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unsatisfactory (2)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Poor (1)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are clear, readable, and well-designed. Text is large enough to be seen from the back of the room. Figures are appropriately sized and labeled. No more than five bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are mostly clear, readable, and well-designed. Text is large enough to be seen from most of the room. Figures are adequately sized and labeled. No more than seven bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are somewhat clear, readable, and well-designed. Text is large enough to be seen from the front of the room. Figures are somewhat sized and labeled. No more than nine bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are unclear, unreadable, or poorly designed. Text is too small to be seen from the back of the room. Figures are too large or too small and unlabeled. More than nine bullet points per slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slides are missing, illegible, or incomprehensible. Text is too small to be seen from anywhere in the room. Figures are irrelevant or absent. Too many bullet points per slide or no bullet points at all.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has a clear introduction, body, and conclusion. Transitions between slides are smooth and logical. Main points are highlighted and supported by evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has an introduction, body, and conclusion. Transitions between slides are mostly smooth and logical. Main points are stated and supported by some evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has an introduction, body, and conclusion. Transitions between slides are somewhat smooth and logical. Main points are mentioned and supported by weak evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation lacks a clear introduction, body, or conclusion. Transitions between slides are abrupt or illogical. Main points are unclear or unsupported by evidence.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation has no discernible structure or flow. Transitions between slides are nonexistent or confusing. Main points are missing or irrelevant.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Demonstration of quality evaluation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate a comprehensive understanding of quality evaluation principles using SonarQube. Presenters provide a comprehensive and detailed overview of the current CI pipeline. Presenters offer insightful and well-reasoned advice on addressing current technical debt, providing clear justification and actionable recommendations. Presenters engage in a thorough and insightful discussion of metrics and tool changes, offering clear rationale and considerations for potential modifications.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate a solid understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, with clear explanations and examples. Presenters provide a clear and informative discussion of the current CI pipeline, covering key aspects with sufficient detail. Presenters provide solid advice on addressing current debt, supported by logical reasoning and relevant examples. Presenters provide a coherent and informative discussion of metrics and tool changes, supported by logical reasoning and relevant examples.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate a basic understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, but with some gaps in clarity or depth. Presenters provide an adequate overview of the current CI pipeline, though some areas may lack depth or clarity. Presenters provide basic advice on addressing current debt, though some aspects may lack depth or specificity. Presenters provide a basic overview of metrics and potential tool changes, though depth and justification may vary.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate poor understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, with significant gaps or inaccuracies. Presenters provide a poor or incomplete description of the current CI pipeline, with significant gaps or omissions. Presenters provide limited or unclear advice on addressing current debt, with weak reasoning or insufficient detail. Presenters offer limited or unclear insights into metrics and tool changes, with weak justification or relevance.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters demonstrate little to no understanding of quality evaluation using SonarQube, with major inaccuracies or misconceptions. Presenters fail to effectively discuss the current CI pipeline, lacking coherence or relevant details. Presenters fail to provide meaningful advice on addressing current debt, lacking coherence or relevance. Presenters fail to effectively discuss metrics and tool changes, lacking coherence or substantive content.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ability to answer questions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer all questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are respectful and courteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer most questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide some additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are respectful and courteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer some questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide little additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are respectful and courteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer few questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide no additional information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are disrespectful or discourteous to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presenters answer no questions from the audience correctly and confidently. Presenters provide irrelevant or inaccurate information or examples when appropriate. Presenters are rude or hostile to the questioners.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id="evaluating-deliverables-based-on-presentation-content"&gt;Evaluating Deliverables Based on Presentation Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="{filename}/group/technical-debt.md"&gt;Group Assignment 5: Technical Debt&lt;/a&gt;, we will use both the content of your report and presentation to grade the 5 points from the deliverables. The weight of the content of the presentation for the main grading is given below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality evaluation using SonarQube (points 1 and 2):  7.5 out of 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussing current CI pipeline (point 3): 2.5 out of 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on paying back current debt (point 4): 3.75 out of 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion of metrics &amp;amp; tool changes (point 5): 2.5 out of 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total presentation content grade: 16.25 out of 70&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note that this section is separate from the presentation marks, which will be graded out of 20 according to the rubric in the &lt;a href="#marking"&gt;table above&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Individual</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/individual.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-03-20:/general/individual.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Individual Assignments&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3 id="assignments"&gt;Assignments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="{filename}/individual/assignment0.mds"&gt;Assignment 0: Getting started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="assignment"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Group Project</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Samuel Iwuchukwu</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;301 Group Project&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#group-project"&gt;Group Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="group-project"&gt;Group Project&lt;/h3&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>How to get Help</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/help.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/help.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Communications Expectations&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#communication-expectations"&gt;Communication Expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#where-to-get-help"&gt;Where to get help?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#discussion-forum"&gt;Discussion Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#office-hours"&gt;Office Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#instructor"&gt;Instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tas"&gt;TAs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#wellness-supports"&gt;Wellness Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#physical-well-being-supports"&gt;Physical Well-being Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#mental-health-supports"&gt;Mental Health Supports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#immediate-assistance"&gt;Immediate Assistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#safety-and-security-for-students"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="communication-expectations"&gt;Communication Expectations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask questions well before Assignment due dates. Although you have nothing to lose by trying, realize that while the course staff try to provide as much support as possible, they are not obliged to answer last-minute questions (i.e., those within less than 2 business days from the assignment due date). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be polite and courteous. We will not tolerate impolite comments or harassments of any sort on the course forum or to any of the course staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="where-to-get-help"&gt;Where to get help?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions about assignments/projects: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due dates: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything where another student might have the same question: Discussion Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions about the material covered in lecture/labs: Discussion forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual help with assignments/projects:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get help &lt;strong&gt;during the labs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend the &lt;strong&gt;office hours of a TA.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend the office hours of your instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal questions about you or your mark: Contact the &lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complaints: Contact the &lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReMarking requests: Contact the &lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;instructor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs will not help you with your marks, even if they're the one who marked it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="discussion-forum"&gt;Discussion Forum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions related to the course and course material, especially if the answer could help another student!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Posting to the discussion forum increases your changes of a &lt;strong&gt;quick response&lt;/strong&gt; since any of the course staff or your classmates are able to answer. 🌠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless your question is personal (E.g., you are feeling unwell and require an EA, you have a question about your mark), all questions should be posted on the Discussion Forum first. Please do not share code from your implementations (configuration settings are OK). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not post your code. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration settings are OK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not post your solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post only questions related to &lt;strong&gt;this course&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be polite, this is not a complaint forum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion forum is on the eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="office-hours"&gt;Office Hours&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your question is related to implementation/configuration issues in the projects/assignments, the TAs are best suited to help you. You can attend TA office hours remotely. &lt;strong&gt;TAs do not provide help outside of Labs and Scheduled Office Hours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your question is related to content covered in class and you need further explanation, please post on the disucssion forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="instructor"&gt;Instructor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/outline.html#contact-information"&gt;Instructor office hours&lt;/a&gt; is in the course outline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="tas"&gt;TAs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you need help with your projects/assignment code, or help getting something working, the TAs are best suited to help you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can attend TA office hours remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not eMail TAs&lt;/strong&gt; unless you're having a hard time joining their Zoom/Meet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs do not provide help outside of Labs and Scheduled Office Hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please be polite and courteous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAs will not re-grade your work or deal with extensions, excuses, illness, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TA office hours are on the eClass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wellness-supports"&gt;Wellness Supports&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2024! I hope that you are happily settling into the winter semester at University of Alberta. If you’re still feeling the stress of exams or hoping to develop good health habits going into this new semester, we’re here to help! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that there are many services available, both in person and virtually, for students to help with physical well being? Whether you need a new exercise class, access to more affordable groceries, or mental health supports, read on to discover what is available at U  of A! Taking care of your physical self can help improve your mental well-being and increase your success in your classes as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few key places to connect with resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="physical-well-being-supports"&gt;Physical Well-being Supports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://campusfoodbank.com/"&gt;Campus Food Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://internalcomms.cmail19.com/t/d-l-vuytlz-ihirhlhytl-k/"&gt;WECAN Food Basket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (affordable groceries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/campus-community-recreation/our-programs/rec-guide/index.html"&gt;Campus and Community Recreation Winter 2024 schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CampusCommunityRecreation"&gt;Campus and Community Recreation Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/counselling/workshops.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Weekly%20free%20mindfulness%20and%20yoga%20class%20through%20Counselling%20%20Clinical%20Services"&gt;Weekly free mindfulness and yoga class through Counselling &amp;amp; Clinical Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://guides.library.ualberta.ca/wellbeing"&gt;Use a treadmill desk when studying in the library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="mental-health-supports"&gt;Mental Health Supports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All mental health &amp;amp; wellbeing supports offered to undergraduate students are listed on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/campus-life/health-wellness/index.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Health%20%20Wellness#mental-health-support"&gt;Health + Wellness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page, including options for peer support programs, medical care, and other wellness programs open to you. Counselling &amp;amp; Clinical Services also offers a range of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/counselling/workshops.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=workshops"&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for you to learn how to be a peer support for other students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unsure how to access a resource, please contact the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/dean-of-students/index.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=Office%20of%20the%20Dean%20of%20Students"&gt;Office of the Dean of Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for a full listing of services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="immediate-assistance"&gt;Immediate Assistance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is in need of immediate assistance, please reach out to a friend, professor, or staff member. Find a list of immediate support services &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/need-help-now.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=WCSI_Jan%202024&amp;amp;utm_content=WCSI_Jan%202024+CID_ba92968704987d94bc0c32e21ef6d5c6&amp;amp;utm_source=cm_internal_comms&amp;amp;utm_term=here"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="safety-and-security-for-students"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UA's &lt;a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/current-students/safety-and-security.html"&gt;Safety and Security for Students&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protective Services &lt;a href="tel:780-492-5050"&gt;780-492-5050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="contact"></category><category term="wellness"></category></entry><entry><title>Labs</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/labs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/labs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lab Procedure, Lab Assignments, Lab Marking&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#lab-things-go-here"&gt;Lab Things Go Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lab-things-go-here"&gt;Lab Things Go Here&lt;/h3&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="labs"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="grading"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning Resources &amp; Reference Materials</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/resources.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/resources.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Resources, Reference Materials, Notes, Videos, Slides&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#software"&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#video-tutorials"&gt;Video Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#reference-materials"&gt;Reference Materials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="software"&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="video-tutorials"&gt;Video Tutorials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="reference-materials"&gt;Reference Materials&lt;/h3&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="references"></category><category term="videos"></category></entry><entry><title>Slides</title><link href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Hazel Victoria Campbell</name></author><id>tag:ualberta-cmput301.github.io,2024-01-06:/general/slides.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Slides and per-topic resources&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#objects-uml-java"&gt;Objects UML Java&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#software-process"&gt;Software Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#agile-planning"&gt;Agile Planning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#design-patterns"&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="objects-uml-java"&gt;Objects UML Java&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/02-OO.pdf"&gt;Objects UML Java Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/OONotes.pdf"&gt;SDA Object-Oriented Design Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/OOGlossary.pdf"&gt;SDA Object-Oriented Design Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="software-process"&gt;Software Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/SPM.pdf"&gt;SPM Introduction to Software Product Management Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/SPM_Gloss.pdf"&gt;SPM Introduction to Software Product Management Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/SPAP.pdf"&gt;SPM Software Processes and Agile Practices Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/SPAP_Gloss.pdf"&gt;SPM Software Processes and Agile Practices Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/Requirements.pdf"&gt;SPM Client Needs and Software Requirements Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/Requirements_Glossary.pdf"&gt;SPM Client Needs and Software Requirements Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="agile-planning"&gt;Agile Planning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/AP.pdf"&gt;SPM Agile Planning for Software Products Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/AP_Gloss.pdf"&gt;SPM Agile Planning for Software Products Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="design-patterns"&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ualberta-cmput301.github.io/general/slides/DP.pdf"&gt;SDA Design Patterns Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="general"></category><category term="resources"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="contact"></category><category term="wellness"></category></entry></feed>